to talk about the consensus layer.
谈论共识层。
I will give Mario a little chance to give Alex a quick interview,
我会给马里奥一个机会，让亚历克斯快速采访，
and then we'll jump right in.
然后我们会直接加入。
Or sorry, introduction, not interview.
或抱歉，介绍，而不是面试。
Yeah, thanks so much, Josh.
是的，非常感谢，乔什。
And thanks, Alex, for being here.
谢谢亚历克斯在这里。
Yeah, so last week, we had Matt, light client,
是的，上周，我们有Matt，Light Client，
explaining the execution layer of Ethereum.
解释以太坊的执行层。
And this week, we have the other half Ethereum covered by Alex here,
本周，我们在这里覆盖了另一半以太坊，
completing the whole big picture of how it works.
完成其工作原理的整个大局。
So yeah, we are very excited to have you here, Alex, because so Alex is part of Ethereum Foundation.
是的，我们很高兴能在这里，亚历克斯，因为亚历克斯是以太坊基金会的一部分。
He's an expert in many important topics that are being worked on these days, like mainly MEV,
他是如今正在从事许多重要主题的专家，例如Mev，主要是Mev，
all the current proposals about PBS, burning MEV, you might heard of are being worked on by Alex.
当前关于PBS，燃烧MEV的所有建议，您可能听说过Alex。
to some extent he works on a bunch of rust software there are many rust people in the
在某种程度上，他在一堆生锈软件上工作，其中有很多生锈的人
study group so uh you might be interested to hear that uh alex uh contributes to many rust projects
学习小组，所以您可能有兴趣听到UH Alex UH有助于许多Rust Projects
and uh most importantly for today he's an expert on the consensus layer of ethereum so uh i hope to
嗯，最重要的是，他是以太坊共识层的专家，所以我希望
learn a lot from you today alex thank you so much for being here again yeah yeah i think yeah i
今天向您学习很多
I think we can check right in and the stage is yours.
我认为我们可以直接入住，舞台是您的。
So before we get started, just want to remind everybody that
因此，在我们开始之前，只想提醒大家
if you have conversation or comments, questions, please
如果您有对话或评论，请提问
post them in the Discord thread, the week three Discord thread.
将它们张贴在Discord线程中，第三周不一致线程。
Go ahead, Alex. Thanks.
继续，亚历克斯。谢谢。
Great.
伟大的。
Thank you for having me.
谢谢你有我。
Can you hear me okay?
你能听到我的声音吗？
Hello.
你好。
it's all good here you go okay thanks sometimes I have uh AV issues anyway
一切都很好，你还好，谢谢，有时我有UH AV问题
um great okay uh yeah I'm Alex Stokes I'm a researcher at the ethereum Foundation uh
嗯，很好，是的，是的，我是亚历克斯·斯托克斯，我是以太坊基金会的研究员嗯
today we'll be looking at ethereum's consensus layer so yeah I think let's see so I'm pretty
今天我们将研究以太坊的共识层，所以是的，我想让我们看看我很漂亮
I can see, let me do this. What? Okay. Well, I think I can at least see questions in the chat.
我可以看到，让我这样做。什么？好的。好吧，我想我至少可以在聊天中看到问题。
So if you have them, just drop them here and we'll try to get to them as we go.
因此，如果您有它们，只需将它们放在这里，我们将尝试随身携带它们。
What I'll try to do is go through some slides just to frame what does consensus even mean?
我会尝试做的就是浏览一些幻灯片，只是为了构建共识是什么意思？
Why do we care about it? And these blockchain contexts. And then I should be able to take
我们为什么关心它？以及这些区块链上下文。然后我应该能够接受
some sort of live notes to, you know, draw some diagrams and give you a little better intuition
您知道的某种现场笔记要绘制一些图表，并给您一些更好的直觉
for the different things I'm talking about. So yeah, we will jump in. And let's see here,
对于我在说的不同的事情。是的，我们会跳进去。让我们看看这里，
I believe you can see this. So I guess somebody speak up if you can't. But yeah,
我相信您可以看到这个。因此，我想有人说如果你做不到。但是，是的，
theorem consensus. So let's dive in. So yeah, I mean, I kind of want to start from the
定理共识。所以让我们潜入。是的，我的意思是，我有点想从
very very beginning and like you know why do we even care about these blockchains in the first
从一开始，就像您知道为什么我们在第一个中甚至关心这些区块链
place um i think like ultimately like the really fundamental thing that they do is they manufacture
我认为最终像他们所做的真正基本的事情是他们制造的地方
digital scarcity right so like you have this notion in the real world of um you know like
数字稀缺性，所以就像您在您所知道的UM现实世界中拥有这个概念一样
if there's i have this example later but let's say i go to the grocery store right and they only have
如果我稍后有这个例子，但是假设我要去杂货店，他们只有
like you know 10 apples like they can't magically make more apples if they like give five apples
就像您知道的10个苹果一样，如果他们喜欢给五个苹果，他们就无法神奇地做更多的苹果
way, they still only have five. And it turns out that like, having this notion of like scarcity in
方式，他们仍然只有五个。事实证明，有这种稀缺的概念
the physical world, there's a lot we can do with it to like, create a lot of value, like at the
物理世界，我们可以做很多事情要做，创造很多价值，例如
bottom line, right? So the question then is like, how can we do this in this digital realm that's
底线，对吗？因此，问题就像，我们如何在这个数字领域中这样做
like kind of taken over all of our lives, and is only becoming more and more important as we go?
就像我们一生所占据的那样，只是随着我们的发展而变得越来越重要？
Yeah, so like the place to start, right, is that we figured out how to make like digital goods,
是的，就像起点一样，正确的是，我们想出了如何制作数字商品的方式，
So all these cat photos on the internet,
所以所有这些猫的照片在互联网上，
digital textbooks that you might see,
您可能会看到的数字教科书，
and yeah, more and more of our world today.
是的，当今我们的世界越来越多。
The thing is, is that you can basically
问题是，您基本上可以
copy all of these things.
复制所有这些东西。
If I give you, again, one of these CAD JPEGs,
如果我再次给你这些CAD JPEG之一，
you can just copy it as much as you want.
您可以根据需要复制它。
There's no way to represent scarcity
没有办法代表稀缺
in this digital world.
在这个数字世界中。
And yeah, there's been a huge history
是的，历史悠久
of this being an issue, right?
这是一个问题，对吗？
So if I have a movie that someone wants to protect,
因此，如果我有某人想要保护的电影，
terms of intellectual property once the movie's out and sort of the internet it can easily be
知识产权的条款一旦电影出版，并且很容易成为互联网
copied there's file sharing with bittorrent and all this and yeah it's kind of a mess
复制的是与Bittorrent共享的文件，所有这些，是的，这是一团糟
and you know the reason people care about these blockchains is because they generate this digital
而且您知道人们关心这些区块链的原因是因为它们产生了这个数字
scarcity and i'll kind of explain why so the reason this is important is because again you can
稀缺，我会解释为什么这很重要的原因是因为您再次可以
use this property to like represent all these things in the physical realm and like our
使用此属性喜欢代表物理领域中的所有这些东西，并喜欢我们
intuitions around them being scarce in this digital space, right?
在这个数字空间中，周围的直觉很少，对吗？
And you can use this for all sorts of things, like money, like tokens.
您可以将其用于各种东西，例如金钱，例如令牌。
These are pretty familiar examples if you're in the blockchain context, but then more generally
如果您处于区块链上下文，则这些是非常熟悉的示例，但更一般而言
like property rights.
喜欢财产权。
So one day you'll probably be able to put the deed to a house on the blockchain.
因此，有一天，您可能可以将契约放在区块链上的房屋上。
And the exciting thing beyond this is that I think there's still a lot more that will
令人兴奋的事情是，我认为还有更多
kind of come out of this, and we're still figuring out what's possible.
有点来自此​​，我们仍在弄清楚什么可能。
So if anything, I think this is a very exciting space to be in.
因此，如果有的话，我认为这是一个非常令人兴奋的空间。
And yeah, it's kind of this fun adventure and we'll see where it goes.
是的，这是一种有趣的冒险，我们将看到它的去向。
The important thing here is that without this blockchain technology, you couldn't have this thing where you could make these like unique digital objects.
这里重要的是，如果没有这种区块链技术，您就无法拥有这样的东西，可以像独特的数字对象一样制作这些东西。
Again, because you could trivially copy like anything before that.
同样，因为在此之前您可以像任何事物一样琐碎地复制。
So and this just like wasn't possible without blockchains.
因此，这就像没有区块链一样。
This is why people care about them.
这就是为什么人们关心他们的原因。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Okay it seems like that's working. Yeah so okay we have these blockchains that give us this like
好吧，似乎在起作用。是的，好吧，我们有这些区块链，使我们像
property of digital scarcity and like let's now try to like think about how we might do this.
数字短缺的财产，就像现在让我们尝试考虑如何做到这一点。
So you know let's just zoom into like one use case again this kind of generalizes to any of
因此，您知道让我们再次像一个用例一样放大这种概括
these notions of like scarce objects we want to think about but let's say we want to talk about
我们想考虑的这些稀缺物体的概念，但假设我们想谈论
digital money right so we have money let's say like it's like there's units of money which are
数字资金正确，所以我们有钱，就像有钱单位
coins right so imagine like i can have coins i can like spend coins um you know it really should
硬币是正确的，所以想象一下我可以拥有硬币，我想花硬币，嗯，你知道应该
fire your intuition of like having money in you know the physical space when we say scarcity here
发射您对金钱的直觉
we mean they're only ever like say end coins at one time right so like if i have 100 coins i can't
我们的意思是他们只是一次像一次说末端硬​​币一样，所以就像我有100个硬币我无法
like spend 200 for example there's like a fixed number at any point in time so
例如，像花200支一样，在任何时间点都有固定的数字，所以
you know i'm not sure what everyone's background is but um either way let's just assume that the
你知道我不确定每个人的背景是什么，但是无论哪种方式，让我们假设
following things make sense uh and again if you have questions just drop them in the chat
遵循事情是有意义的，如果您有疑问，请在聊天中放弃它们
so right okay so you know we'll we'll kind of have this like straw man example right so like
好吧，好吧，你知道我们我们会有一个像稻草人的榜样，对
you might be familiar with like a web server running in like you know what we call web2 so
您可能会熟悉像Web服务器一样，就像您知道我们称为Web2的内容一样
i don't know something like facebook meta or like uh you know instagram all these different social
我不知道像Facebook meta之类的东西，或者像呃，您知道Instagram所有这些不同的社交
media platforms twitter which i guess we now call x either way you just imagine that you have some
媒体平台Twitter，我想我们现在以任何方式称呼X，您只是想象您有一些
money protocol you can like write software to implement the rules of this protocol and it just
货币协议您可以喜欢写软件来实施此协议的规则，它只是
runs on someone's web server and the big thing here is that whoever's operating the server you
在某人的网络服务器上运行，这里最大的事情是谁在操作服务器的人
you trust them to make sure that there are no double spins.
您相信他们可以确保没有双旋转。
And this is again, kind of the core property
这再次是核心属性
that we wanna get out of our blockchains.
我们想摆脱区块链。
And I have these examples here,
我在这里有这些例子，
again it should really mirror your intuition
再次应该反映您的直觉
from the physical world, right?
来自物理世界，对吗？
So if I'm at the grocery store,
所以，如果我在杂货店，
let's say the grocery store has like 100 apples,
假设杂货店有100个苹果，
if they sell me one apple, then they only have 99 left.
如果他们卖给我一个苹果，那么他们只剩下99。
They can't go make like 200 apples, 300 apples, right?
他们不能像200个苹果，300个苹果那样做，对吗？
can't um i mean yeah they can't just magically make apples they have a certain number and if they
嗯，我的意思是的，他们不能仅仅神奇地制作苹果，他们有一定的数字
give some away then that's that now in our money protocol you can imagine it's a similar thing
然后放弃一些，那就是现在在我们的货币协议中，您可以想象这是类似的事情
where you know if i only have 100 coins in the protocol and i send you five i only have 95 left
在您知道我是否只有100个硬币的地方，我给您发送了5个我只剩下95个硬币
when we say double spend we kind of mean this thing where out of my 100 if i send you five
当我们说双重花费时，我们有点意思是我的100中，如果我给你发送了五个
I should definitely have 95. I can't send you five, you know, like I can't send
我绝对应该有95个。我知道，我知道，我无法发送五个
more than two people 50 coins each, right? Because I would just not have that many points.
每个人都有两个以上的50个硬币，对吗？因为我不会有那么多积分。
And the important word here is that you're trusting the operator, right?
重要的词是您信任操作员，对吗？
And historically, we've never been able to like trust an operator to like uphold this sort of
从历史上看，我们从来没有能够喜欢信任操作员喜欢这样的坚持
protocol. And in particular it's like double spin property. So there's like a number of ways this
协议。特别是它就像双旋转属性。所以有很多方法
can happen. One of them is just like a bug in the software that's implementing our money protocol.
可能发生。其中之一就像在软件中实现我们的货币协议的错误一样。
And, you know, what it's going to look like is the server like accidentally makes extra
而且，您知道，它的外观是服务器，就像偶然地使额外
coins, right?
硬币，对吧？
So let's say they commit to only being like 1000 coins.
假设他们只承诺像1000枚硬币一样。
And you know, there's some bug and suddenly there's like 1001 coins, right?
而且您知道，有一些错误，突然之间有1001个硬币，对吗？
For us using this protocol, that's like not quite fair.
对于我们使用此协议而言，这不太公平。
We want there to only be the number that they claim.
我们希望只有他们声称的数字。
And it's, you know, again, a bug if somehow there's more.
如果有更多的话，这是一个错误。
The fact that there's a single operator, central server that's coordinating all this, it's
有一个单一操作员，中央服务器正在协调所有这些，这是
also an issue on the security front, because it could simply be an active attack.
这也是安全方面的问题，因为它可能只是一个主动攻击。
So maybe there is a bug, maybe the operator themselves is not in a position to exploit
因此，也许有一个错误，也许操作员本身无法利用
the bug, for example, because they don't want to.
例如，由于它们不想这样做，因此该错误。
They want people to believe that their money protocol is good.
他们希望人们相信他们的货币协议很好。
But an attacker could compromise the server and then trigger the bug in their own way
但是攻击者可以妥协服务器，然后以自己的方式触发错误
way, and make these extra coins for themselves.
方式，并为自己制作这些额外的硬币。
And if we've all believed that these coins are useful for some reason, this is directly
如果我们都相信这些硬币由于某种原因很有用，那是直接的
profitable for the attacker, so they're incentivized to do it.
攻击者有利可图，因此他们激励他们这样做。
You could even have another scenario where the operator themselves is just simply not
您甚至可以有另一个场景，而操作员本身就是不只是
honest, right?
老实说，对吗？
So if I control this money protocol, and people like the money protocol, maybe I'm just making
因此，如果我控制此资金协议，以及喜欢货币协议的人，也许我只是在做
a few extra coins on the side, because again, it's profitable for me to do so.
侧面有一些额外的硬币，因为再次，我这样做是有利可图的。
particular like this is the key point here is that if you ever make one of these protocols
特别是这样的关键是，如果您制作了这些协议之一
where someone is incentivized to um you know if there's a way for them to profit from this
在激励某人的地方，您知道是否有办法从中获利
like basically they will just it's a matter of time um and yeah the reason we're using this in
就像基本上他们一样，他们只是时间问题，是的，我们在使用它的原因
the first place is because these coins are valuable for some reason and so again it's
首先是因为这些硬币出于某种原因很有价值，所以再次
like there's this direct financial incentive for people to actually attack this thing
就像人们有直接的经济激励措施使人们真正攻击这件事
so okay because of all this you know we kind of get to this problem where this trusted operator's
好的，因为所有这些
not great um so what can we do well try to get rid of it very simple solution uh as we'll see
不好嗯，我们能做些什么，尽力摆脱它非常简单的解决方案，嗯，我们会看到
this has led to like decades of research into like how to actually do this uh it's actually
这导致了数十年来的研究，例如如何真正做到这一点
quite tricky so let me just check the chat to see okay i guess everyone's still following so okay
非常棘手
A key point here is that, to the extent that you can make a credible protocol that everyone
这里的一个关键是，在一定程度上，您可以制定一个可靠的协议
can trust, the more useful it will be.
可以信任，它将越有用。
I'm speaking very broadly or abstractly, because it's a key point to get across that if you
我的讲话非常广泛或抽象，因为如果您
want to make something that's maximally useful, it needs to be minimally trusted.
想要制作最大有用的东西，需要最低限度地信任。
Let's say we have two operators and one of them is pretty good but sometimes has issues.
假设我们有两个操作员，其中一位很好，但有时遇到问题。
Their money is just not as good as another operator who never has any of these bugs
他们的钱不如另一个从未有这些错误的运营商好
I listed above. So to the extent that we can drive towards this trust minimized setting,
我在上面列出。因此，在一定程度上，我们可以朝着这种信任最小化的设置，
the more useful our abstraction of this digital scarcity will be, and the better this will be in terms of creating value for people.
我们对这种数字稀缺性的抽象越有用，就为人们创造价值而言，这越好。
And we should care about this because, you know, there's so much value we see in the world by having structures to handle physical scarcity
我们应该关心这一点，因为，您知道，我们在世界上看到的有很多价值来处理身体短缺
that you would expect we could do a similar thing for digital scarcity, right?
您希望我们可以为数字短缺做类似的事情，对吗？
And as you've seen with the growth of Bitcoin, Ethereum, and everything else, right, a lot of people care.
正如您所看到的，比特币，以太坊的成长以及其他所有人都在乎。
There's a lot of value that will come out of this. There could be applications we haven't thought of
从中有很多价值。可能有我们没有想到的申请
yet that would do it more. So it's a very worthy goal. So let's try to think about how would we
但这会做更多的事情。因此，这是一个非常值得的目标。因此，让我们尝试考虑我们将如何
remove this strong man protocol with this single trusted operator. It turns out it's pretty hard.
用这个可信赖的操作员删除这个强大的人协议。事实证明这很难。
So again, sort of the obvious thing is you're like, hey, I have this thing. There's one single
再次，显而易见的是，您就像，嘿，我有这个东西。有一个
party, that is a point of failure. Obviously, it's a very direct thing to say, get rid of the single
党，这是失败的点。显然，这是一件很直接的事情，摆脱单身
leader here, the single operator. The way you would think about doing this, rather than having
领导者，单个操作员。您会考虑这样做的方式，而不是
one node in the system that controls everything, you distribute the protocol across all the nodes.
系统中的一个节点可以控制所有内容，您可以在所有节点上分配协议。
Luckily, there's a very rich academic literature on distributed computation,
幸运的是，有关于分布式计算的非常丰富的学术文献，
and maybe from there we can learn some things about how to do this
也许从那里我们可以学习一些有关如何做到这一点的知识
for the context we care about.
对于我们关心的上下文。
And generally how people have thought about this is
通常人们对此的看法是
rather than just have one node in the system,
而不是只有一个系统中的一个节点，而是
you now have end nodes, which all compute the same thing.
您现在有结尾节点，所有节点都在计算同一件事。
So if you think about it, if we have this money protocol,
因此，如果您考虑一下，如果我们有这个钱协议，
what are we actually doing?
我们实际在做什么？
People can mince money in the protocol.
人们可以在协议中赚钱。
Let's say I want to buy 100 coins.
假设我想买100枚硬币。
Then also you can transfer things in the protocol.
然后，您也可以在协议中传输内容。
Let's say I want to send five coins from me to you.
假设我想向您发送五枚硬币。
Okay?
好的？
From there, you can think about this as all of the,
从那里，您可以将这些视为所有人，
like the way that we're gonna structure this now
就像我们现在要结构的方式
so that we can have everyone sort of join the system,
这样我们就可以让每个人加入系统，
these end nodes I'm talking about join the system
这些结束节点我正在谈论加入系统
and work together, you structure them in a way
并一起工作，您以某种方式将它们构造
that they compute the same thing
他们计算同一件事
given all these inputs, right?
鉴于所有这些输入，对吗？
So we assume that everyone has all the same inputs
因此，我们假设每个人都有相同的输入
to the protocol, which if you think about it,
对于协议，如果您考虑它，
it's just a record of all the transactions. Like when we mint coins, you could also imagine like
这只是所有交易的记录。就像当我们铸造硬币时一样，您也可以想象
burning coins or something to withdraw. But either way, there's ways to like get in and out of the
燃烧硬币或其他东西。但是无论哪种方式，都有可以喜欢进出的方法
system. And there's ways to like transfer these coins within the system, right? And if you take
系统。有一些方法可以喜欢在系统中传输这些硬币，对吗？如果你接受
the entire list of the entire history of this whole sort of economy we're building, you can
我们正在建立整个经济的整个历史的整个清单，您可以
imagine if you just like sort of sum these inputs in the same way, you'll get a single output,
想象一下，如果您喜欢以相同的方式概括这些输入，那么您将获得一个输出，
right? In this case, a single output would just be our current ledger of everyone's balance.
正确的？在这种情况下，单个输出将是我们目前对每个人的平衡的分类帐。
So at any point in time, we can ask the end nodes, like, hey, you know, what are everyone's balances in the system, right?
因此，在任何时间点，我们都可以问结束节点，例如，嘿，您知道，系统中每个人的平衡是什么，对吗？
If I started with 100 coins, I spent five to you.
如果我从100个硬币开始，我花了5枚。
Now suddenly it says I have 95 and you have five points.
现在突然它说我有95分，你有5分。
And if you think about it, you could do this for, you know, any sequence of transactions we make.
而且，如果您考虑一下，您可以为此做到这一点。
At any point in time, you can look at the sort of summary, which is this output.
在任何时间点，您都可以查看此输出的摘要。
it. So going back to this, like academic literature and all the work that's been put into this, you
它。因此，回到这一点，就像学术文学和所有工作一样，您
know, over the past couple of decades, this concept is called state machine replication.
知道，在过去的几十年中，这个概念称为状态机器的复制。
The replication here is referring to the fact that, you know, we have multiple nodes in the
这里的复制是指以下事实：您知道，我们有多个节点
system. They essentially all duplicate, you know, the same work, this like input log to get the
系统。他们本质上是所有重复的，您知道，这是相同的工作，就像输入日志一样
same output. And in particular, this is what we mean by consensus is that every node in the system
相同的输出。特别是，这就是我们共识的意思是系统中的每个节点
should eventually agree on the outputs.
最终应该同意输出。
So again, you write your program, your protocol
再一次，您编写程序，协议
as this like deterministic function of the inputs.
就像输入的确定性函数一样。
You imagine then that if you have an honest node,
您想象那时，如果您有一个诚实的节点，
they're going to run the same function on the same inputs.
他们将在相同的输入上运行相同的功能。
They have to get the same output, right?
他们必须获得相同的输出，对吗？
Like assuming there are no bugs or anything in the protocol
就像假设协议中没有错误或其他任何内容
for the same set of inputs, you get the same output.
对于相同的输入，您将获得相同的输出。
This is useful to get rid of our single trusted operator
这对于摆脱我们的单一可信赖的操作员很有用
because as the number of nodes increases,
因为随着节点的数量增加，
the system becomes harder to attack.
系统变得更难攻击。
Rather than exploiting a bug, say, on one node and taking down the whole system, you now have to say maybe attack two or three or maybe all of them.
您现在不得不说攻击两三个或所有这些。
There's this notion of a majority in the system, and this is really what I mean when we say consensus, is that at any point in time, there should be some majority of nodes that all have the same view or the same output, the same state.
系统中有大多数的概念，这确实是我说共识时的意思是，在任何时间点，应该有一些大多数节点都具有相同的视图或相同的输出，相同的节点状态。
So when they do this, then even if some of the nodes are faulty, you still have a majority of them saying, like, this is the state of the world, right?
因此，当他们这样做时，即使某些节点是错误的，您仍然有大多数节点说，这是世界的状态，对吗？
And so this is the idea is that it becomes much harder now to attack our system as we have more nodes who are doing the same thing.
因此，这就是想法是，现在攻击我们的系统变得更加困难，因为我们有更多的节点在做同样的事情。
Okay.
好的。
Very little chat.
聊天很少。
I'll assume everyone's following along.
我假设每个人都在跟随。
Let's see here.
让我们在这里看看。
One second.
一秒钟。
Yeah, just to be clear, Alex, that a lot of the chat is happening in Discord, so there's not much YouTube chatter or chat in this particular platform.
是的，要清楚，亚历克斯（Alex），在Discord中进行了很多聊天，因此在此特定平台中没有太多YouTube聊天或聊天。
So Mario and I will chime in if there are any important questions or comments to be said since you're not looking at it.
因此，马里奥和我会说有任何重要的问题或评论要说，因为您不在查看它。
Okay, great. Thank you.
好吧，太好了。谢谢。
Yeah, I can also try to find the Discord, but that might be a side quest for me.
是的，我也可以尝试找到不和谐，但这可能是对我的辅助任务。
So anyway, yeah, just let me know if there's something I should address.
所以无论如何，是的，只要我应该解决问题。
And okay, let's jump back in.
好吧，让我们跳回去。
So the point here is that we want to increase the number of nodes in the system.
因此，这里的重点是我们要增加系统中的节点数量。
And if all of our software is cracked and our variants hold, then it becomes much harder to
如果我们的所有软件都破裂并且我们的变体都可以满足，那么很难
attack. So this notion that I'm circling around in the literature around consensus, this is referred
攻击。因此，我在文献中围绕共识中四处乱逛的观念，这是提到的
referred to as Byzantine fault tolerance.
称为拜占庭的容错。
So the logic goes, okay, if more nodes in the system means it's more secure, then we
因此，逻辑是，好的，如果系统中的更多节点意味着它更安全，那么我们
want a very high number of nodes.
想要大量的节点。
I'm calling it in here, it's a very high number.
我在这里称呼它，这是一个很高的数字。
And you can imagine the limit, this is like every node on the Internet, right?
您可以想象限制，这就像Internet上的每个节点一样，对吗？
Like your refrigerator could participate, your computers at home, all the computers
就像您的冰箱可以参与的一样，您的计算机在家，所有计算机
in these data centers, I don't know, your car driving down the highway, you can imagine
在这些数据中心，我不知道，您的汽车沿着高速公路行驶，您可以想象
everything connected to the internet can like participate in this protocol.
连接到Internet的所有内容都可以参与此协议。
And then you have an incredibly high number of nodes it becomes
然后，您的节点数量非常高
incredibly hard to attack the system.
难以置信的攻击系统。
So the thing is, is though, as you move to this setting on the public internet,
因此，事实是，当您在公共互联网上转到此设置时，
the internet is this like, again, permissionless open system, people
互联网就是这样，同样是无许可的开放系统，人们
can join and leave and, and doing so things can start going awry.
可以加入并离开，这样做可能会开始出现问题。
So to give some examples, you know, let's say we have like 20 nodes on the internet.
因此，举一些例子，您知道，假设我们在互联网上有20个节点。
the internet is a faulty system. And so, for example, some nodes could simply miss messages
互联网是一个错误的系统。因此，例如，有些节点可能会简单地错过消息
from other nodes. If I go to my local node at home and I send it, hey, transfer some coins
来自其他节点。如果我在家里去本地节点，然后发送它，嘿，转移一些硬币
from me to you, it could just be the case that for no reason other than chaos on the internet,
从我到你，可能只是没有其他原因，除了互联网上的混乱之外
my transaction doesn't end up getting to enough nodes to be part of the consensus.
我的交易最终并没有达到足够的节点来成为共识的一部分。
There could be bugs implementation.
可能会有错误实现。
So you can imagine that, you know,
因此，您可以想象，您知道，
we have all these nodes out there
我们有所有这些节点
and they have like different implementations
他们喜欢不同的实现
in the same software.
在同一软件中。
And again, as long as there's a correct implementation,
再说一次，只要有正确的实现，
right, they'll compute the same output, everything's good,
是的，他们会计算相同的输出，一切都很好，
but there could be a bug.
但是可能会有一个错误。
And so maybe some nodes kind of fall off the network
因此，也许有些节点从网络上脱落
or see a different view.
或看到不同的视图。
There can also be hardware failures.
也可能存在硬件故障。
So this is kind of similar to like a failure
所以这与失败类似
just in like the transport of the internet,
就像互联网的运输一样
you could imagine, you know, I'm running the money protocol on my toaster and my toaster goes down
您可以想象，您知道，我在烤面包机上运行了货币协议，而我的烤面包机则下降了
because I'm like making toasts and it doesn't have enough resources to also process the
因为我喜欢做烤面包，而且它没有足够的资源来处理
transactions, right? And so for maybe some short period of time, this node would go off offline.
交易，对吗？因此，也许在短时间内，这个节点会离线。
Or there could be an active attack. Again, going back to the previous thing where, you know,
否则可能会有积极的攻击。再次，回到上一件事，您知道，
if this is a useful or valuable protocol, people then are directly incentivized to like try and
如果这是有用或有价值的协议，那么人们将直接激励去尝试和尝试
break it. So someone could be actually actively attacking some subset of nodes in the network.
打破它。因此，有人实际上可以积极攻击网络中的某些节点。
And all of these types of things, we want to call this Byzantine fault. And again,
所有这些类型的东西，我们都想称这是拜占庭的故障。再一次，
this is coming out of the academic literature, but the idea is that if we have one of these
这是从学术文献中出来的，但想法是，如果我们有其中之一
consistent protocols running, we want to make sure that it's tolerant to any arbitrary failure
运行一致的协议，我们要确保对任何任意失败都容忍
that could happen, right? So again, there could be a bug, a node could be acting incorrectly or
那可能会发生，对吗？因此，再次可能会有一个错误，一个节点可能不正确地行动或
dishonestly, whatever happens, we want to be sure that, you know, at least on some time scale,
不诚实，无论发生什么，我们都想确保，至少在某些时间范围内，
eventually you get to the place where a majority of nodes have the same view.
最终，您可以到达大多数节点具有相同视图的地方。
If not, then there's a consensus failure and yeah, our protocol's broken.
如果没有，那么会有共识失败，是的，我们的协议被打破了。
So yeah, if you want to really dig into this go look up Byzantine fault tolerance. Again,
所以，是的，如果您想真正挖掘此此查找拜占庭式容忍度。再次，
there's like a lot of literature out there about this, even, you know, pre-crypto,
关于这个文献很多，即使您知道，
but the idea is that basically, okay, we assume some nodes are actually just faulty in this way.
但是想法是，基本上，我们假设有些节点实际上是有缺陷的。
some fraction f are faulty we still want to make a consensus vertical such that we can agree on the
某些比例F是错误的，我们仍然希望将共识垂直，以便我们可以就可以达成共识
outputs uh even in the presence of this faulty fraction and again there's there's a lot we can
即使存在这个故障的分数，输出uh也可以
go into here um we'll kind of focus on ethereum so i'll just briefly touch on these but at a high
进入这里，我们会专注于以太坊，所以我将简要介绍这些以太坊，但很高
level um the general way to think about this is what they call two-phase commit so what this means
级别UM考虑到这一点的一般方法是他们所说的两相提交，这意味着什么
is that assume we have our end nodes in the network, and then basically, you know, one or
是假设我们在网络中有终点节点，然后基本上，一个或一个或
some number of the nodes says, hey, I think the next state of our protocol is, you know, x, I
一些节点说，嘿，我认为我们的协议的下一个状态是，x，我
don't know, some random state, say, incorporating our, you know, the most recent transfers in the
不知道，某些随机状态，例如，将我们的最新转移纳入了
system, those most recent transfers would then take the balance at time t to a different set
系统，这些最新的转移将在时间t上余额到另一组
of balances at time t plus one. And the way this two-phase commit works, there's again two phases,
时间t加1的余额。这两个阶段提交的工作方式，又有两个阶段，
The first phase is, you know, let's say there's some node in the system that says, hey, I think the next day is this.
您知道，第一阶段是系统中有一些节点说，嘿，我认为第二天就是这样。
They kind of send the state to everyone, meaning all the other nodes in the network.
他们将国家发送给每个人，这意味着网络中的所有其他节点。
All the other nodes then have to acknowledge that.
然后，所有其他节点必须承认这一点。
And then once you've seen a Byzantine fault tolerant fraction, say two thirds, you end up in this place where I know that I'm going to have a majority agree with me because they've already done so.
然后，一旦您看到拜占庭的容忍分数，说三分之二，您最终会在这个地方，我知道我将有多数人同意我的意见，因为他们已经这样做了。
So that's phase one.
所以那是第一阶段。
And then phase two then is saying, basically, I just accept that this is the new state of the protocol.
然后第二阶段说，基本上，我只是接受这是协议的新状态。
And the way this works is that, again, assuming that I've reached my fault tolerant threshold, say, you know, two thirds, then there's no way that like there could be another majority view anywhere else in the system.
而且，这种工作的方法是，同样，假设我达到了容忍的宽敞阈值，例如，三分之二的三分之二，那么系统中的其他任何地方都无法像其他多数观点一样。
And again, there are many examples of this that people have actually built out.
再说一次，人们实际上已经建立了许多例子。
This is a problem people had long even before crypto, just as we tried to scale the internet
这是人们甚至在加密货币之前很久以前遇到的问题，就像我们试图扩展互联网一样
doing this exact same thing, you'd have many nodes out there and you wanted them to be tolerant
做这个完全相同的事情，您会有很多节点，您希望它们宽容
these types of failures. In particular culminating in PBFT, this stands for practical Byzantine fault
这些类型的失败。特别是在PBFT中达到顶点，这代表实用的拜占庭断层
tolerance. And it's a protocol that basically lets you do this. The issue though is that
宽容。这是一个基本上让您这样做的协议。问题是
with PBFT and many of these more classical BFT protocols, they kind of were limited in node count
使用PBFT和许多这些更古典的BFT协议，它们在节点计数中受到限制
In particular, you get this quadratic message passing a PBFT, in part because it's a two-phase
特别是，您会收到此二次消息传递PBFT，部分原因是它是两阶段
commit. What we mean here is that if there's say, like, you know, ten nodes in the network,
犯罪。我们的意思是，如果有说明，例如，您知道网络中的十个节点，
they have to exchange say, 100 messages to actually agree that this is the state and that
他们必须交换发言，100条消息实际同意这是国家，
also everyone else sees this as the same state. What this means is that these systems are kind
另外，其他所有人都将其视为同一状态。这意味着这些系统很友善
of limited in how many nodes you can have. The point I was trying to get across a second ago is,
有限的节点有限。我试图跨越一秒钟前的观点是，
especially for these things like you know making uh these systems that represent digital scarcity
特别是对于这些事情，例如您知道使这些代表数字短缺的系统
in like a very secure way you actually want the node count to go much higher than what we could
以一种非常安全的方式，您实际上希望节点计数要比我们能做的要高得多
practically get with these types of protocols and again if you want to dig more into this uh this
实际上，使用这些类型的协议，如果您想进一步挖掘这个问题，uh
general problem is the byzantine generals problem where they're trying to get are they're trying to
一般问题是拜占庭将军的问题，他们正在尝试解决
like solve this right we want to be able to come to consensus with like a very high number of nodes
就像解决这个权利一样，我们希望能够以很高的节点达成共识
even in the presence of some malicious or some Byzantine fraction.
即使存在一些恶意或一些拜占庭分数。
And for a while, this is kind of the state of the research, and that was the best we could do.
有一段时间，这是研究的状态，这是我们能做的最好的。
People were researching this, but ultimately, yeah, we're kind of just moving along until
人们正在研究这一点，但最终，是的，我们只是继续前进直到
the advent of Bitcoin. So I'll talk a bit now about, you know, we're moving into the crypto
比特币的出现。所以我现在要谈谈，您知道，我们正在进入加密货币
context before we go on alex um we got a question here uh nana is asking does the uh does the pbft
在进行Alex UM之前，我们在这里遇到了一个问题，UH Nana问的是UH是否在PBFT
protocols have like an upper bound and if yes what is that practically speaking yeah good question
协议像上限一样，如果是的话，那实际上是什么好问题
so it's not that there's like a hard upper bound it's more that the more nodes you would add the
因此，并不是说像硬上限一样
more overhead and so uh for example the system would be slower right like if you have 10 nodes
更多的开销，因此，例如，如果您有10个节点
joining the protocol, then you can say, you know, process messages with, like, I don't know,
加入协议，然后您可以说，您知道，与我不知道的处理消息，
for example, let's say, like, you know, a couple hundred milliseconds of latency. As you went to,
例如，假设您知道，几百毫秒的延迟。当你去
like, 100 nodes, then you can imagine, you know, there's this, like, much bigger scaling of the
就像，100个节点，然后您可以想象，有这样的节点，例如，更大的缩放
overheads. And then at a certain point, you know, if it's going to take us, like, minutes to agree
开销。然后，在某个时刻，您知道，如果要带我们去同意的话
on the next state of our, like, all of our transactions, then the system starts to become
在我们的下一个状态，就像我们所有的交易一样，系统开始变成
less useful. And, you know, this is a problem, for example, if we want to do something, like,
有用不那么有用。而且，您知道，这是一个问题，例如，如果我们想做一些事情，例如
okay let's do like visa which is this like credit you know credit card network they process like you
好的，让我们喜欢签证，就像信用一样，您知道他们像您一样正在处理的信用卡网络
know i don't know thousands if not more of transactions per second um and you get to a
知道我不知道成千上万的交易，每秒的交易
place where if you want that same level of throughput your consensus protocol for like a
如果您想要相同水平的吞吐量，则可以像
high number of nodes beyond just like the few you know trusted visa servers uh it takes too long
大量的节点超出了您所知道的少数值得信赖的签证服务器的时间
um and in general there's this like trade-off basically between like throughput and latency
嗯，总的来说，这基本上是像吞吐量和延迟之间的权衡
and you know um these consensus protocols are not magic they're bound by the laws of physics
而且您知道这些共识协议不是魔术，它们受物理定律的约束
and so they you know have to follow the same same constraints right
因此，他们知道必须正确遵循相同的约束
um yeah hopefully that was helpful yeah thank you so okay great so um
嗯，希望这很有帮助，是的，谢谢你，好吧，嗯
right there was a bit of a like innovation um with bitcoin this is what everyone got very
是的，有点像比特币一样的创新，这就是每个人都非常喜欢的
excited about originally with crypto is like, in some sense, you know, Satoshi, the creator of
最初对加密货币感到兴奋，就像在某种意义上，您知道，Satoshi，
Bitcoin, proposes the system that, you know, in some sense solves this Byzantine generals problem.
比特币提出的系统在某种意义上解决了这个拜占庭将军问题。
So the cool thing here is that it scales to an arbitrary node count. So like, you can kind of
因此，这里很酷的是它会扩展到任意节点计数。所以，你可以
get past this bottleneck of having, you know, some set number of nodes agree. And in particular,
越过这种瓶颈，有一定数量的节点同意。特别是
right, the way the system is designed is anyone can like join or leave. And again, the system,
是的，系统的设计方式是任何人都可以加入或离开。再次，系统，
you know, together is like very tolerant to this type of behavior. There's a consensus that we'll
您知道，在一起就像这种行为非常宽容。我们有一个共识
look at in a second that gets you to the same state. And yeah, nodes can freely come and go
在一秒钟内查看，使您进入同一状态。是的，节点可以自由地来去去
and you kind of get through, you know, you get around the scalability bottleneck.
而且，您知道，您可以通过可扩展性瓶颈来度过难关。
So in particular, Bitcoin has this notion of proof of work. You take this proof of work,
因此，特别是，比特币具有这种工作证明。您取得此证明，
and it also in the same, at the same time, gives you this notion of like weight to a chain or
同时，它也使您对链的重量类似或
difficulty. And the consensus algorithm is pretty straightforward. You just look at the chain out
困难。共识算法非常简单。你只是看链条
there that you can observe just from the public internet, and you pick the heaviest chain or the
在那里您可以从公共互联网上观察到，然后选择最重的链或
one with the most work done. And if you do this, as long as you have the same view of the chain as
一个工作最多的工作。如果您这样做，只要您对链的看法与
everyone else, you'll eventually get to the same state of the chain. Because assuming there's an
其他所有人，您最终都会达到链条的同一状态。因为假设有一个
honest majority of nodes in the network, they're going to all be following the same protocol.
诚实的大多数网络节点，他们都将遵循相同的协议。
they're going to all follow the heaviest chain. And if you do this, you end up in the same place.
他们将遵循最重的链条。如果这样做，您最终进入了同一地方。
So, let me see what's next. Okay. Yeah. So, let me actually move now to I'm going to draw
所以，让我看看下一步是什么。好的。是的。所以，让我现在实际移动到我要画画
some diagrams to kind of unpack what I just said. And I'm going to need a second to get this set up.
一些图可以解开我刚才说的话。而且我需要一秒钟才能进行设置。
Okay, let's see.
好吧，让我们看看。
We'll do that.
我们会这样做。
And then I think I'm going to have to stop this, but I'll come back here.
然后我想我将不得不停止这个，但我会回到这里。
And okay.
好的。
So I believe you can see this.
所以我相信你可以看到这个。
So, okay, what do we mean here?
所以，好吧，我们在这里是什么意思？
So the way to think about this is that we start from some initial state.
因此，考虑到这一点的方法是我们从某种初始状态开始。
This is like the Genesis block in Bitcoin.
这就像比特币中的创世纪块。
it doesn't really matter what it is, but you know,
这是什么都没关系，但是你知道，
we have our little block here,
我们在这里有小街区，
I'll put a G on it for Genesis.
我将其放在创世纪上。
And the idea now is that anyone who wants to join the system,
现在的想法是，任何想加入系统的人，
they come and they can add a block, right?
他们来了，他们可以添加一个块，对吗？
So let's say then we have like a bunch of transactions
然后，假设我们有一堆交易
out here, I'll just do some like little dots.
在这里，我只是做一些小点。
And these are the transactions that are saying, you know,
这些是交易说的，你知道，
I'm gonna send one Bitcoin from me to you,
我要向我发送一个比特币，
we'll send like half a Bitcoin over here,
我们将在这里发送一半比特币，
whatever they do, right?
他们做什么，对吗？
These like, just transfers in the system.
这些都只是在系统中传输。
The way that this works is that if I want to propose a block, and again, anyone can do this.
这种起作用的方法是，如果我想提出一个块，然后再一次，任何人都可以做到这一点。
We'll see kind of how this works in a second.
我们将在一秒钟内看到这种工作方式。
But basically, I like bundle all of these up and then I make a block.
但基本上，我喜欢所有这些捆绑，然后我做一个障碍。
So there's a block here.
所以这里有一个街区。
I'll go ahead and delete these because we move them somewhere else.
我会继续删除这些，因为我们将它们移到其他地方。
And yeah, there's like a couple of things going on here.
是的，这里有几件事。
So the key thing to realize here in Bitcoin is that there's this like proof of work notion.
因此，在比特币中要意识到的关键是，有这样的工作概念。
Proof-of-work is it's like, again, yeah, this notion that basically when I see this message,
工作证明是，是的，是的，这个想法基本上是当我看到此消息时，
there's some cryptography involved such that I know a certain amount of work or computational
涉及一些密码学，使我知道一定数量的工作或计算
power was dedicated to this block. One way to kind of think about it is you're sealing the block,
电源专门用于这个障碍。一种考虑它的一种方法是您密封块，
you're adding this special thing that can prove to anyone no matter what it took a certain amount
您正在添加这个特殊的东西，无论花多少钱，都可以向任何人证明
of work to produce. And the way this works is basically there's this notion of cryptographic
生产的工作。基本上，这种工作方式是加密的概念
cache where you know i give it some data i get back this like unique sort of like digest um
缓存您知道我给它一些数据，我会像摘要一样回到这个数据，就像摘要一样
and yeah basically the only way to get this digest because these hashes are like somewhat random
是的，基本上是获得此摘要的唯一方法，因为这些哈希就像是随机的
the only way to get this is like i must have just computed the hash there's like no way around that
获得这一点的唯一方法是我一定刚刚计算出的哈希
so the first thing you do well i mean there's a couple things you do but
所以你做得好的第一件事，我的意思是你做几件事，但是
um you know imagine now we have our block and then we have like all our transactions in here
嗯，你知道现在我们有了我们的街区，然后我们喜欢这里的所有交易
okay um you know so one cool thing is that this block is going to reference the hash
好吧，你知道，很酷的一件事是，这个块将引用哈希
of the previous block and this is like this arrow here it's like this pointer um you do this just so
在上一个块中，这就像这里的箭头一样
you can actually establish a history because you know if i just had some block over here
您实际上可以建立历史
that's just like floating off in space you know i need to know like the context of how these
就像在太空中漂浮在一起，您知道我需要知道这些方式
transactions should be sequenced because ultimately you know um maybe we'll think about it this way
交易应进行排序，因为最终您知道嗯，也许我们会这样考虑
you want there to be like a unique sequence so imagine this you know i'm drawing transactions
您希望那里像一个独特的序列，所以想象一下您知道我正在绘制交易
here and you know this is like you know plus five bitcoin to like some other account a
在这里，您知道这就像您知道的，再加上五个比特币，喜欢其他帐户
you know plus 0.5 of some account b whatever they are um there should be a unique sequence
您知道加上某些帐户B的0.5 b无论他们um什么都应该有一个唯一的序列
and this is why we need consensus to get this unique sequence and then anyone can just basically
这就是为什么我们需要共识才能获得这个独特的顺序，然后任何人都可以基本上可以
replay them all and you end up at the end with the same state you know account a has whatever
全部重播它们，您最终以与您知道的帐户相同的状态而结束
account b has whatever account c has whatever you know i don't know uh three bitcoin two bitcoin you
帐户B有任何帐户C有您所知道的任何我不知道的uh三币两个比特币
know 24 bitcoin whatever it ends up being so the way we do this is again we need this like unique
知道24比特币无论最终发生什么，所以我们这样做的方式又来了，我们需要它像独特
sequence that we're going to kind of represent or like serialize with these blocks and so you need
我们将代表或喜欢与这些块序列化的顺序，因此您需要
this notion of like parent block so the way you do this is basically you have like a hash of this
这种类似父母块的概念，所以您的做法基本上是您喜欢这个哈希
thing, I'll say h of g, you actually just write h of g in this block, and this basically says,
这件事，我要说的是G，您实际上只是在此障碍物中写下g，这基本上说，
okay, I know that this is, here, maybe I'll, well, let's try this.
好的，我知道这是，在这里，也许我会尝试一下。
Hash of g. Either way. Hopefully this is clear. Sorry it's a little cramped. But basically you
g。无论哪种方式。希望这很清楚。对不起，有点狭窄。但基本上你
have the hash of this previous block and this one, and again, the way these cryptographic hash
具有以前的块的哈希，这是这些加密哈希的方式
functions work is that there's no way for me to know this hash of the previous block unless I
功能工作是，除非我
have the previous block. So you have that it has all the transactions in here and then also now
有以前的块。因此，您有它在这里和现在都有所有交易
there's this proof of work which you know the way we can think about it is it's just like this like
有这样的工作证明，您知道我们可以考虑的方式就是这样
seal of approval put a little check mark that says I did some amount of computation to actually make
认可的印章给我做了一些计算标记，说我做了一些计算以实际制作
this block. Okay there's a couple things going on here so the first thing we get is that um
这个块。好吧，这里有几件事，所以我们得到的第一件事是
This proof of work is this rate limiter thing or this notion of civil protection.
这项工作证明是这种限制的事情或这种民事保护的概念。
So this is a big thing in, again, these open permissionless systems that anyone can join.
因此，这再次是这些任何人都可以加入的无许可系统的大事。
You need to have some way to limit how many blocks can be made at a given time.
您需要有一些方法来限制在给定时间可以制作多少个块。
Otherwise, you get, you know, there's now like 10 trillion blocks waiting out here
否则，您知道，现在有10万亿个街区在这里等待
and it's a mess. My toaster's going offline because it can't even handle this many blocks
这是一团糟。我的烤面包机脱机，因为它甚至无法处理这么多块
and we have a big problem. So the first thing that all these different proof of work or proof
我们有一个大问题。因此，所有这些不同的工作证明或证明的第一件事
mistake which we'll get to in a second the way these protocols work is they have some notion
这些协议的工作方式是我们有一些概念的错误
of like the civil resistance meaning that you know on a reasonable amount of time only sort of one
就像公民抵抗意味着您在合理的时间里只知道
person let's say or like a few people can can make one of these updates or new blocks at a given time
人说或喜欢一些人可以在给定时间进行这些更新或新块之一
so let's clean this up a little bit um the other thing now is that and this is like you know one
因此，让我们清理一点一点，现在另一件事是，就像您知道的那样
of the insights of bitcoin is that not only do we get this simple protection with this proof
比特币的见解是，我们不仅通过此证明获得了这种简单的保护
for work, it can be used for consensus. The way this would work now, let me zoom out a little bit
在工作中，它可用于共识。现在的工作方式，让我放大一点
if I can figure this out. So, yeah, let me actually just clean this up a little bit.
如果我能解决这个问题。所以，是的，让我实际上只是清理一点。
So, the way this would work is that, you know, now let's say there's, like,
因此，这可以工作的方法是，现在，假设有，
a few blocks in the chain. Okay, cool. And okay. I'll just draw a few more for fun.
链中的几个街区。好吧，很酷。好的。我只是为了娱乐而抽一些。
So we have these blocks in the chain.
因此，我们在链中有这些块。
And again, the way this would work is that you, you know, maybe start from your Genesis
再说一次，这将起作用的是，您知道，也许是从创世纪开始的
state, which could be like, no one has any coins and you can now just replay all the
状态，可能没有人有任何硬币，您现在可以重播所有
transactions, just going block by block and sequence.
交易，只是按块和序列进行。
And again, it's the state machine replication idea where if I have the same inputs, we all
同样，这是状态机器复制的想法，如果我有相同的输入，我们都
have a, you know, correct implementation of our money protocol.
您知道，请正确实施我们的货币协议。
We all end up with the same outputs, which in this case, for example, would be, you know,
我们所有人最终都以相同的输出来进行，例如，在这种情况下，您知道，
our ledger at some point in time.
我们的分类帐在某个时间点。
So we do this and write.
所以我们这样做并写。
The other thing here now is that with this proof of work,
现在，这里的另一件事是，有了这项工作证明，
this is notion of difficulty,
这是困难的想法，
which we don't really need to get super into the weeds
我们真的不需要超级杂草
about this works, but ultimately,
关于这项工作，但最终
there's a notion of difficulty,
有困难的概念，
which is how much work a particular proof work represents.
特定的证明工作代表了多少工作。
A way to think about it is it's just a number.
思考它的一种方法只是一个数字。
So we could say, okay, this is like first block in the chain
所以我们可以说，好吧，这就像链中的第一个街区
here, maybe had difficulty like 15,
在这里，也许很难15，
and these are like arbitrary numbers.
这些就像任意数字。
All you really need is that they are, you know, numbers that increase.
您真正需要的是，它们是增加的数字。
So, you know, let's say there's difficulty 15 here.
因此，您知道，假设这里有困难15。
The next block has even like difficulty one.
下一个块甚至很难一个。
So that will be interesting in a second because it's not strictly increasing, but it's just more.
因此，这将在一秒钟内很有趣，因为它并没有严格增加，但这只是更多。
And then, you know, I don't know, let's say there's like 2000 work on this last block.
然后，您知道，我不知道，假设在最后一个区块上有2000年的作品。
So now this algorithm is like pretty simple.
因此，现在这种算法就像很简单。
and again this was like part of well it's a whole conversation about bitcoin and simplicity but
再次，这就像一部分的一部分，这是关于比特币和简单性的整个对话
ultimately um the way to think about this is that this is very simple uh to do and this was like a
最终，考虑到这一点的方式是，这很简单，这就像一个
you know something that's very attractive about epic about bitcoin at least is that the way i
您知道至少对比特币非常有吸引力的东西是我的方式
find the head of the chain meaning like the the most recent block is i just sum these up and i
找到链的头，就像最近的块一样，我只是总结了这些，我
take the one with the most work.
以最多的工作为例。
And this is what I meant by heaviest a second ago.
这就是我一秒钟前的意思。
So here we would say that we have, I don't know, I guess it should be better
所以在这里我们会说我们不知道，我想应该更好
numbers, but that would be what 16 and 2000.
数字，但这就是16和2000。
So, you know, total work here, total difficulty, uh, it would be, you know, 2016.
因此，您知道，这里的总工作，完全困难，呃，这将是2016年。
Okay.
好的。
Uh, there's no fork in this chain.
嗯，这条链中没有叉子。
So this is actually it's trivial.
因此，这实际上是微不足道的。
You wouldn't need to actually even look at this.
您甚至不需要实际查看。
You would just go to the most recent block and say, that's that the chain.
您只会去最近的街区说，那就是那个链条。
Okay.
好的。
Let's look at another example now where it's a little more complicated.
现在让我们看一个更复杂的示例。
And let's say we have this.
假设我们有这个。
And then okay.
然后还可以。
So again, the way to think about this is like anyone can come and propose a block really
再说一次，考虑到这一点的方式就像任何人都可以来提出一个块
at any time.
随时。
So let's say that we are, you know, over here somewhere at this state of the chain, maybe
假设我们知道，我们在这种链条状态的某个地方，也许
back at the first block.
回到第一个街区。
And then now someone else is going to come along and they're going to make another block.
然后，现在其他人将会出现，他们将又有一个障碍。
And let's say, yeah, we'll do it this way.
是的，是的，我们这样做。
So let's say someone makes a competing block,
假设有人做一个竞争的障碍，
kind of around the same time as our second block here,
与我们的第二个街区大约在同一时间
but their block has a difficulty,
但是他们的街区很难
I don't know, we'll say 10.
我不知道，我们会说10。
The details actually get a little more complicated,
细节实际上变得更加复杂，
but this should give you some intuition for how this works.
但这应该为您提供一些工作原理。
Let's say this has difficulty 10,
假设这很难10，
and then someone else comes along and makes another block
然后有人来了
that has difficulty, like, yeah, I don't know, 3000.
这很难，例如，是的，我不知道，3000。
So I missed the block, sorry.
所以我错过了街区，对不起。
So we have this like very heavy block over here.
因此，我们在这里有非常沉重的街区。
So now the way to think about this is
所以现在考虑这一点的方法是
we now have all these blocks floating around.
现在，我们将所有这些块漂浮在周围。
Like let's say again, we have our toaster
就像再说一遍，我们有烤面包机
running on this network and it's seen this set of blocks.
在此网络上运行，并看到了这组块。
We need to pick one unique head of the chain.
我们需要选择一个独特的链条。
Now, because, you know, a block can only commit
现在，因为您知道，一个块只能提交
to one parent, you know, you have this sequence
对于一个父母，您知道，您有此序列
where you could basically have,
您基本上可以拥有
let's see if I can do this.
让我们看看我是否可以做到这一点。
There's a chain here, right?
这里有一个连锁店，对吗？
There's also a chain here.
这里还有一条链。
And this is just following these parent linkages.
这只是遵循这些父母链接。
So you start, I maybe say, you know, this leaf,
所以你开始，我可能会说，这片叶子，
which would be, how do I get back to the other color?
哪个是，我如何回到另一种颜色？
Okay, this is fun.
好吧，这很有趣。
um i guess i'll do this so you know we start say from like this block uh and this block and then
嗯，我想我会这样做，所以你知道我们从这个块uh和这个块开始说，然后
the way this would work is there's now sort of these competing heads of the chain and we still
这种工作方式是现在有这些竞争的链条，我们仍然
want to get back to this like single you know single sequence so we need to apply this algorithm
想要像单一序列一样回到单个序列，所以我们需要应用此算法
now to get to one head of the chain right which is picking basically this block or this block
现在，要右转到一个链的一个头，基本上是在基本上挑选此块或该块
And in Bitcoin, we follow this difficulty number, we sum them up, and basically we say,
在比特币中，我们遵循这个困难数字，总结它们，基本上我们说，
okay, looking at the top chain it has difficulty 2016, looking at the bottom chain, we get,
好的，看着2016年的顶级链，看着底部链，我们得到了，
you know, what is that? 3,025, right? So yeah. So the intuition here is that basically we saw
你知道，那是什么？ 3,025，对吗？是的。因此，这里的直觉是我们基本上看到了
this bottom chain, well, we saw both chains, and we need to pick one, and we just simply
这条底部链，好吧，我们看到了两个连锁店，我们需要选择一个，我们只是简单地
to pick the one with more work done.
挑选一个完成的工作。
So in that case, what we would say is that,
因此，在这种情况下，我们要说的是，
let me maybe make this green,
让我做这个绿色，
that this is the current head of the chain, right?
这是链的当前负责人，对吗？
And in particular, that means that all of this other,
特别是，这意味着所有这些
like this competing fork of the chain, this one,
像这个链条的竞争叉一样，这是
let me use this color.
让我使用这种颜色。
So this chain here, the red chain,
所以这条连锁店，红链，
basically we just ignore it, right?
基本上我们只是忽略了它，对吗？
And this is cool now because yeah,
现在很酷，因为是的，
anyone can come and join the system as they please.
任何人都可以随意加入系统。
If I maybe missed this history,
如果我可能错过了这个历史，
but I'm coming online now,
但是我现在上网了，
I just downloaded the same set of blocks
我刚刚下载了相同的块
and independent of anyone else,
并且独立于其他任何人，
I can just follow this difficulty,
我可以遵循这个困难，
which is again, just a consequence of this hash function.
再次，这只是该哈希功能的结果。
And yeah, it's clear to me what that the chain is.
是的，这对我很明显。
If I wanna go make another block,
如果我想一个街区，
then I know that the way I do that
那我知道我这样做的方式
it's just make one here that has parent here
只是在这里做父母
and the system keeps going, right?
系统不断运转，对吗？
Okay.
好的。
Let's see, I'm gonna switch back to the slides now.
让我们看看，我现在要切换回幻灯片。
Hopefully that made sense.
希望这是有道理的。
I know that, yeah, there's,
我知道，是的，有
oh, I'll just, hopefully, I hope that it makes sense.
哦，我希望，我希望这是有道理的。
Let me go back here.
让我回到这里。
So great.
太好了。
So, yeah, I was trying to get across this notion that there's this proof-of-work thing.
所以，是的，我试图弄清有工作证明的事情。
Hopefully my diagram made it a bit clear that anyone can download these messages from the
希望我的图表清楚地表明，任何人都可以从
Internet and there's a way to find a unique chain, even in the presence of competing chains.
互联网，即使在竞争连锁店的存在下，也有一种方法可以找到独特的链条。
Now, just to use some of these words that we were using a minute ago, right?
现在，仅使用一分钟前使用的一些单词，对吗？
So this is like structured as a state machine replication.
因此，这就像结构化作为状态机的复制。
The inputs to the system are these transactions.
系统的输入是这些交易。
So they're just Bitcoin transactions organized into blocks that, you know, spend Bitcoin
因此，它们只是组织成比特币交易的块，您知道，花比特币
here and there.
这里和那里。
And the output, again, is just like replaying all these transactions in a unique chain,
同样，输出就像在独特的链中重播所有这些交易一样，
you get back a unique state of the ledger.
您将获得分类帐的独特状态。
There's some things you can do here around using cryptography to like reduce the possible,
您可以在这里使用密码学以减少可能的可能性，可以做一些事情，
you know, I'm calling it the state space.
你知道，我称之为状态空间。
But, like, in particular, if I just make a transaction, I probably want to, like, have it be signed.
但是，特别是，如果我只是进行交易，我可能想签署它。
So you know it's uniquely for me.
所以你知道这对我来说是独特的。
It's, like, authorized for me to actually move the coins and not just have them out there.
就像我授权真正移动硬币，而不仅仅是把它们放在那里。
I mentioned this thing about the parent hash, right?
我提到了有关父母哈希的这件事，对吗？
Because otherwise you could imagine kind of like when I was drawing the, like, sea of blocks off to the side.
因为否则您可以想象像我在绘制街区大海时一样。
It greatly reduces, like, how complex this, like, this protocol can be.
它大大降低了这种协议的复杂程度。
This, like, algorithm you have to compute.
就像您必须计算的算法一样。
if you can restrict how many options you can have, right?
如果您可以限制可以有多少个选项，对吗？
And again, cryptography here is very useful for this.
同样，这里的密码学对此非常有用。
In particular, you don't have to trust
特别是，您不必信任
some other third party to tell you these things
其他一些第三方告诉你这些事情
because you can just run the cryptography locally
因为您可以在本地运行加密
and get to the same facts yourself.
并自己解决同样的事实。
So again, we're reducing trust in the system.
因此，我们正在减少对系统的信任。
Then you use proof-of-work
然后您使用工作证明
to implement the consensus here.
在这里实现共识。
And again, there's this notion of civil protection
再说一次，有这种民事保护的概念
where you just have to do some amount of work
您只需要做一些工作的地方
before the blocks even consider valid.
在块之前，甚至考虑有效。
And then in the same breath, you know, this is kind of a cool thing about Bitcoin is that it
然后，同样的呼吸，您知道，这对比特币来说是一件很酷的事情
leverages this in multiple ways, but not only do you get similar protection, but you also can use
以多种方式利用这一点，但您不仅得到了类似的保护，而且还可以使用
this notion of difficulty to implement your consensus, right? And to give you one unique
实现您的共识的困难概念，对吗？并给你一个独特的
chain. There's another cool bit with like these cryptocurrencies that they also, you know,
链。像这些加密货币一样，还有另一个很酷的地方。
have this like native currency they can issue, right? So you just make up this money protocol.
他们可以发行像原始货币一样，对吗？因此，您只需弥补这个钱协议即可。
you can actually then also hand out money as rewards to incentivize people to actually,
然后，您实际上也可以将钱分发给奖励，以激励人们实际上
you know, extend the state of the chain. Because again, remember, we're now in the setting where
您知道，扩展链的状态。因为再次，请记住，我们现在处于
it's a permissionless open system. Anyone can come and join without some incentive to actually,
这是一个无许可的开放系统。任何人都可以加入而没有任何动力，实际上
like, add another block to the chain. You might imagine that no one cares, right? And so then
就像，在链条中添加另一个块。您可能会想象没有人在乎吧？所以
it's just like the protocol stops. Right. So then you have these rewards and, you know,
就像协议停止一样。正确的。因此，您将获得这些奖励，并且知道，
it it seems to work like bitcoin's still running uh people care about it and yeah that's pretty cool
它看起来像比特币还在运行UH的人关心它，是的，这很酷
okay so hopefully this gives you some notion of what we mean when we talk about consensus
好的，希望这给您一些关于我们谈论共识时的含义的想法
in these distributed protocols um that was bitcoin just because it's usually like a pretty
在这些分布式协议中，比特币只是因为它通常就像一个漂亮的
straightforward simple way to think about this stuff and now we'll turn to ethereum so
直接思考这些东西的简单简单方法，现在我们将转向以太坊，所以
So in general, so yeah, it, yeah, there's a lot to say here, but basically Ethereum
所以总的来说，是的，是的，这里有很多话要说，但基本上是以太坊
today is in this proof of stake consensus that I'll explain it more in a second.
今天是在这种股份共识的证明中，我将在一秒钟内对此进行更多解释。
Previously we had a proof work consensus mechanism.
以前，我们有证明工作共识机制。
There's this event called the merge that basically swapped us from work to prove it's tech.
有一个称为合并的事件，基本上使我们下班以证明其技术。
And I'll talk about that more in a second.
我将在一秒钟内更多地谈论。
But ultimately, yeah, we now have this consensus layer of Ethereum that uses this proof-of-stake
但最终，是的，我们现在拥有使用此列出证明的以太坊共识层
protocol.
协议。
So let's look at that.
因此，让我们看一下。
Generally, moving from proof-of-work to proof-of-stake, the idea is rather than use this what I'm
通常，从工作证明转变为验证证明，这个想法而不是使用它
calling an exogenous signal for the protection of consensus, namely this work you put in
呼唤外源信号以保护共识，即您投入的这项工作
to compute this right block hash to signal this is a valid block and it can go into the
要计算此正确的块哈希以发出信号，这是一个有效的块，它可以进入
chain, we're going to use an endogenous signal.
链，我们将使用内源信号。
And here I mean, with respect to the protocol, right?
我的意思是，关于协议，对吗？
So the protocol itself can see now
因此协议本身现在可以看到
because we have this notion of stake.
因为我们有这个股份的概念。
So the idea is you have some coins, in this case, Ether,
所以想法是您有一些硬币，在这种情况下，以太
you lock up Ether as sort of like, you know,
您将以太锁定为某种像，您知道，
this like risk capital or the stake in the system.
就像风险资本或系统中的股份一样。
And this is compared to say like work in Bitcoin
这与比特币中的工作相比
where the work is like this thing that's just happening.
就像这件事一样发生的事情。
Like the Bitcoin protocol itself
像比特币协议本身
has no way to understand what work was done.
无法理解做什么工作。
Like you can't, yeah, it's like it's not it's this thing that comes from outside the system.
是的，是的，就像不是这是来自系统外部的东西。
So hopefully this point's clear.
因此，希望这一点很清楚。
It turns out that doing this is really useful because now that you have a protocol representation of this thing we're going to use for consensus, the stake, you can do a lot more with it.
事实证明，这样做真的很有用，因为现在您已经有一个协议表示，我们将用于共识，股份，您可以对此做更多的事情。
So that's kind of the second point around incentive concerns.
因此，这是围绕激励问题的第二点。
But I'll just briefly touch on the first point, which is energy usage.
但是我只是简要介绍第一点，即能量用法。
So, you know, people were and still are very concerned that the way this proof of work works is there's now almost this race to like toss as much work as you can into the system.
因此，您知道，人们曾经和仍然非常担心这种工作证明的方式现在几乎有这场竞赛喜欢折腾的工作，尽可能多地进行系统。
This is good for the security system because the more work, the harder it is to make a competing block and sort of reorg the system to like some other history.
这对安全系统来说是有益的，因为工作越多，就越难进行竞争障碍，并将系统重新构成像其他历史记录一样。
But then at the same time, you have people just like dumping energy into the system.
但是与此同时，您有像将能量倾倒到系统中一样。
And, you know, especially if you don't think Bitcoin is useful or valuable, then it seems like it's wasted in some sense.
而且，您知道，尤其是如果您认为比特币没有用或有价值，那么从某种意义上说，它似乎浪费了。
So there was this push and still is this push to think about, you know, more energy efficient ways we can design the systems.
因此，有这种推动力，但仍然是思考我们可以设计系统的更节能方式的推动力。
And that was a lot of the motivation for moving to proof of stake.
这是转向股份证明的许多动机。
So at the same time, there is also incentive concerns around proof of work itself.
因此，与此同时，关于工作证明本身也存在激励问题。
And again, this kind of gets to the fact that there's no way like you can you can get rewards for work.
同样，这种事实是，您无法获得工作奖励。
You can like invite people to do this work to like add blocks to Bitcoin.
您可以邀请人们做这项工作，喜欢在比特币中添加块。
But there's no way to like then turn around and punish them or like take away these rewards if they don't do what you want.
但是，如果他们不做您想做的事，就没有办法喜欢转身并惩罚他们或取走这些奖励。
So you kind of almost have like half of, you know, the way to think about it is like carrot and stick.
因此，您几乎有一半的思考方式就像胡萝卜和棍子一样。
There's like a stick or rather, sorry, there's a carrot, right?
有一根棍子，或者更确切地说，对不起，有胡萝卜，对吗？
So you can hand out these carrots with Bitcoin, which are more Bitcoin.
因此，您可以用比特币的比特币分发这些胡萝卜。
But there's no stick to say, okay, if you do something bad, if you try to actively reorg the chain or just something like this, you know, I'm going to like swat you with the stick.
但是，没有话要说，好吧，如果您做得不好，如果您尝试积极地重新整理链，或者只是这样的东西，您知道，我会喜欢用棍子Swat。
and uh proof of stake because you then have the actual consensus like resource within the
和uh的股份证明，因为您在
protocol itself it actually gives you a lot more flexibility around implementing this like stick
协议本身实际上为您提供了更大的灵活性，例如棒子
right in particular what we mean is you can actually hand out penalties for bad behavior
尤其是我们的意思是您实际上可以为不良行为分发处罚
not just rewards this reduces the tax surface and generally makes the system more secure
不仅奖励这会降低税收表面，而且通常使系统更安全
and yeah okay so we'll dig into proof of stake ethereum so you know at a very high level it
是的，好的，所以我们会挖掘以太坊的利益证明，所以你知道它在很高的水平上
it looks a lot more like these traditional BFT protocols.
它看起来更像是这些传统的BFT协议。
And again, I'll try to throw up some diagrams
再说一次，我会尝试扔一些图
to make that more clear.
为了更清楚。
There's an initiative validator.
有一个计划验证器。
So, the system is still permissionless
因此，该系统仍然是无许可的
to the extent that anyone can join,
在任何人都可以加入的范围内
but they do have to put up the stake,
但是他们确实必须放大股份，
which today is like 32 ETH.
今天就像32 ETH。
And the way this is gonna work
而这将运作的方式
is that you essentially run something like two-phase commit
是您本质上运行类似两阶段的订单
like I was talking about a second ago.
就像我在谈论一秒钟前一样。
And once you have it BFT majority,
一旦您拥有BFT多数，
so once say two thirds of the chain has signed off
因此，一旦说三分之二的链条已签约
on some unique state of the chain,
在链的某些独特状态下，
there's no way to sign off,
没有办法签字，
have the majority sign off on another chain
在另一个链上有多数签名
without there being what we call equivocation
没有我们称之为模棱两可的
or again, some conflict.
或再次，一些冲突。
And because there's this resource
而且因为有这个资源
within the protocol of the stake,
在股份的协议中，
if we do observe one of these equivocations
如果我们确实观察到这些模棱两可之一
or one of these faults or conflicts,
或这些故障或冲突之一，
we can actually delete stake of the actors
我们实际上可以删除演员的股份
who messed up, so to speak, right?
可以这么说，谁搞砸了，对吗？
So, every action is essentially signed.
因此，每个动作都基本上签署了。
And so you can actually have the protocol itself
因此，您实际上可以拥有协议本身
ingest these messages and you can say,
摄取这些消息，您可以说，
hey, you know, a majority of the evaluators
嘿，你知道，大多数评估者
said this was the chain,
说这是链
sometime later they wanted to reorg
后来他们想重新
to a different state of the chain,
到另一个链的状态，
but this is actually in conflict.
但这实际上是冲突。
And so when they do this, you can then say,
因此，当他们这样做时，您可以说，
hey, this is bad, I'm gonna ignore this other state,
嘿，这很糟糕，我会忽略另一个状态，
and moreover, I'm going to punish you somehow.
而且，我将以某种方式惩罚您。
This is what we mean when we talk about slashing
这就是我们谈论削减的意思
is that basically we can start
是基本上我们可以开始
to then even just delete the stake
到那时甚至删除股份
when we observe one of these faults.
当我们观察到这些故障之一时。
So ultimately, especially compared to these work chains,
因此，最终，尤其是与这些工作链相比
it's less resource-intensive, more secure.
它的资源密集程度较低，更安全。
Sounds pretty cool. So yeah,
听起来很酷。是的，
I'm going to switch back to
我要切换回
my little whiteboard over here and try to go
我的小白板在这里尝试去
through some of the details of the Proof-Stake protocol.
通过证明Stake协议的一些细节。
This is probably a good time for questions if anyone has them.
如果有人有问题，这可能是一个疑问的好时机。
There are a couple of questions here.
这里有几个问题。
Okay. Um, one question about is that there's a significance in the, uh, 32 ETH denomination
好的。嗯，一个问题是，嗯，32 ETH教派有重要意义
for staking. Sure. Yeah. So there is, um, and it gets back again to the same bottleneck we
用于静止。当然。是的。所以有，嗯，它又回到了我们的同一瓶颈
were talking about a second ago, where there's this trade-off between how much throughput or
在谈论一秒钟前，在多少吞吐量或
like how, how much your system can process over a given time and how long it takes.
就像如何在给定时间内处理多少系统以及需要多长时间。
And the idea of the 32 ETH is that it's like striking some spot in this trade-off between there being too many validators, meaning too much overhead, meaning it takes too long to actually like come to consensus, versus there being too few and the system not being as secure.
32 ETH的想法是，这就像在验证太多的验证器之间取消了一些折衷，这意味着太多的开销，这意味着实际上要花太长时间才能真正达成共识，而不是很少系统不那么安全。
it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much it's pretty much
几乎这几乎是它几乎是它的几乎是
less signatures, which is this cryptographic construct that lets you actually aggregate
较少的签名，这是该加密结构，可让您实际汇总
messages.
消息。
So rather than have to process say like a hundred messages, you can aggregate them into
因此，您可以将它们汇总到
one and you know, from the same amount of work, you can basically do one processing
一个，您知道，从相同数量的工作中，您基本上可以进行一个处理
that would say it for a hundred, right.
那会说一百，对。
And because of this, we could actually scale the system.
因此，我们实际上可以扩展系统。
And you know, what this meant then concretely is that, rather than have, you know, fewer
而且您知道，这是什么意思是，而不是，而不是更少
validators or something for the same data accounts, we could actually lower the stake
验证者或其他数据帐户的东西，我们实际上可以降低股份
required.
必需的。
So that's why you have the 32.
这就是为什么您拥有32。
Cool, thank you.
酷，谢谢。
One other question.
另一个问题。
Is there an upper limit to the number of validators
验证器数量是否有上限
in proof of stake?
在股份证明？
Theoretically, no.
理论上，不。
But again, you'll hit practicalities
但是再次，您会达到实用性
of these being systems out in the real world.
这些是现实世界中的系统。
So we have just under a million validators
因此，我们只有不到一百万个验证者
on main net right now.
现在在主网上。
The core devs very much are concerned
核心开发人员非常担心
about getting you know even like two million right like there's been it's sort of there's been like
关于让您知道即使像200万正确的人一样
many many optimizations we've had to put into the protocol uh especially like the implementation to
我们必须在协议中进行许多许多优化，特别是喜欢实施
even get to this amount um we have our hlshq test net that's just over 1.5 million and it works but
即使达到这一数量，我们的HLSHQ测试网刚刚超过150万，它有效，但
you know we definitely do like sort of these like more ephemeral test nets uh these like dev nets
您知道我们绝对喜欢这些，就像更多的短暂测试网uh一样
to actually see how high we can go and basically yeah the number um you know i don't think we can
实际上，我们可以去有多高，基本上是的，你知道我不知道我们可以
comfortably go much past that. So, you know, at the very end, if we have time, I'll touch
舒适地超越了这一点。所以，你知道，最后，如果我们有时间，我会触摸
on some future directions of things we're thinking about today. And one of them is very much figuring
在未来的某些方向上，我们今天正在考虑的事情。其中之一是很重要
out actually how to reduce the value of your account for this reason.
实际上，出于这个原因，如何减少帐户的价值。
Great. Mario, any other questions you want to surface?
伟大的。马里奥，您想遇到的其他问题吗？
I think it's good for now.
我认为现在很好。
So go ahead.
所以继续。
Okay, great.
好吧，太好了。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
And it has the little emoji reacts.
它的表情符号很小。
Let's see, let me just double check.
让我们看看，让我仔细检查。
I think time-wise, we're okay, like 30 minutes.
我认为时间很及时，我们还可以，大约30分钟。
Okay, let's see here.
好吧，让我们在这里看看。
Okay, let me switch back to my whiteboard.
好吧，让我切换回白板。
And, okay, we should be good with this.
而且，好的，我们应该对此保持良好状态。
So, okay, this was my previous scribbling
所以，好吧，这是我以前的抄写
around Bitcoin consensus.
围绕比特币共识。
So we're now going to look at,
所以我们现在要看
yeah, let me just get a new page.
是的，让我获得一个新页面。
I could just do this.
我可以做到这一点。
Apparently I can't.
显然我不能。
This is great.
这很棒。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, we'll do it like this.
是的，我们这样做。
So, okay.
所以，好的。
Sorry.
对不起。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
Let's look at Ethereum proof of stake.
让我们看一下以太坊的股份证明。
So, yeah, let me think about where I want to begin.
所以，是的，让我考虑我想从哪里开始。
I guess it's just like to set the stage.
我想这就像设定舞台。
Within Ethereum, we have these end protocol consensus actors, the validators.
在以太坊内，我们拥有这些最终协议共识参与者，即验证者。
And yeah, the validators do quite a bit.
是的，验证者做了很多。
And this is maybe a little confusing because you don't it is actually something I think
这也许有点令人困惑，因为您没有，这实际上是我认为的
people have a misconception about around Ethereum generally is that you don't need to lock up 32Eth
人们对以太坊周围的误解通常是您不需要锁定32th
to be a validator to validate the protocol. Anyone can join the protocol. I can go run a
成为验证协议的验证器。任何人都可以加入协议。我可以跑步
flow node right now that doesn't... I'm not a consensus actor in the protocol, but I'm still
流节点现在不是...我不是协议中的共识演员，但我仍然
running, I'm still validating all the blocks I see, running the consensus that the validators
跑步，我仍在验证我看到的所有块，运行验证者的共识
provide, and I get to the same state. And this is actually important because the validators
提供，我达到了同一状态。这实际上很重要，因为验证者
are honestly trusted, right?
诚实信任，对吗？
They have this penalty,
他们有这种罚款，
like they have this,
像他们有这个
we have this way to penalize them
我们有这种惩罚的方式
in the protocol.
在协议中。
But as I'll probably get to later,
但是，正如我以后可能要去的那样
you can get to a place where
您可以到达一个地方
even if the, you know,
即使您知道，
consensus is like correct,
共识是正确的，
the consensus could be on like a chain
共识可能像链
that doesn't implement
那无法实现
something we agreed to.
我们同意的事情。
Like if there is a malicious majority,
就像有恶意的多数一样，
even of the validator set,
甚至验证器集，
they could decide to say,
他们可以决定说，
hey, the actual consensus
嘿，实际共识
was over this like block
像块一样
where, you know,
你知道，哪里
we printed a million ETH
我们印刷了一百万个ETH
to all the validators.
给所有验证者。
This would be like a strong violation of like the protocol, right?
这就像对协议这样的强烈侵犯，对吗？
Because again, we have a notion of what Ethereum should do.
因为再次，我们对以太坊应该做什么有一个概念。
There's like this Ether asset and, you know, everything on top in the ABM.
像这样的醚资产，您知道，在ABM顶部的所有内容。
And, you know, it should still follow the rules.
而且，您知道，它仍然应该遵守规则。
Like the validators should have no special role in here other than provide this like
就像验证者在这里不应该在这里没有特殊角色
consensus function.
共识函数。
And we still want to hold them accountable and keep them in check.
而且我们仍然希望让他们负责并保持检查。
And the way that we do this is like we run the nodes ourselves, right?
我们这样做的方式就像我们自己运行节点一样，对吗？
So going back to Bitcoin for a second, you know, everyone running Bitcoin,
因此，回到比特币一秒钟，你知道，每个人都在运行比特币，
even if you're not adding blocks to the chain,
即使您没有在链条中添加块，
you know, acting as this miner,
你知道，作为这个矿工，
you're still checking the protocol,
您仍在检查协议，
again, to keep the miners accountable.
同样，要让矿工负责。
Same thing here where, you know,
同样的事情，你知道，
you still want to validate the protocol,
您仍然想验证协议，
even if you're not one of these consensus validators.
即使您不是这些共识验证者之一。
So hopefully that's clear.
所以希望这很清楚。
So the way this works is you have validators.
因此，此工作的方式是您拥有验证器。
Today, if you want to like join the system,
今天，如果您想喜欢加入系统，
you know, you like find your 32 ETH,
你知道，你喜欢找到32 ETH，
which these days is a lot of money,
这些天有很多钱，
but you have the 32 ETH, you send it to the special place in the EVM. And, you know,
但是您拥有32 ETH，将其发送到EVM中的特殊位置。而且，你知道，
I'll kind of assume you guys generally understand how this works, at least in broad strokes,
我会假设你们通常会理解这是如何工作的，至少在广泛的笔触中，
because of yesterday, or sorry, the last talk, looking at an execution layer. But only you send
由于昨天或对不起，最后一次谈话，看执行层。但是只有你发送
your 32 ETH to this deposit contract. And there's a way then, okay, actually, I'll draw that out.
您的32 ETH签订了此存款合同。然后有一种方法，好吧，实际上，我将其提出来。
Let me finish this contract. This is now a really important thing to understand
让我完成这份合同。现在这是一个非常重要的事情
is that there's a consensus layer, CL, and an execution layer. Basically, now there's two
是有一个共识层，CL和一个执行层。基本上，现在有两个
almost different parts of the protocol that work together. Before the merge, these things were
协议的几乎不同部分共同起作用。在合并之前，这些事情是
kind of like uh you know they kind of were like one one unit and the part this was because the
有点像嗯，你知道他们有点像一个单元，这是因为
the consensus protocol was pretty work it was like relatively simple compared to like proof
共识协议很漂亮，与样品相比，相对简单
of stake as you'll see there's a lot going on um and for you know complexity reasons security
股份，因为您会看到很多事情正在发生，因此您知道复杂性的原因安全
reasons and also historical reasons uh this new purchase dickens layer was developed kind of in
原因和历史原因嗯，这是新的购买狄更斯层的一种
parallel and so that's like why we had the merge uh was to basically um bring in this new consensus
平行，这就是为什么我们要合并的原因是基本上是要提出这个新的共识
layer to to add consensus to the chain and replace the proof-of-work setting so let's see yep there
层以添加链条共识并更换工作证明设置，所以让我们在那里看看是的
we go so there's a consensus layer and one way to think about this is that there's almost like
我们走了，所以有一个共识层，一种思考的方法是，几乎有
two different chains here right so there's like the consensus layer that's making consensus blocks
这里有两个不同的连锁店，所以就像共识层一样，正在达成共识块
and there's also like this execution layer that you know in some sense is also producing blocks
从某种意义上说，您知道的执行层也是如此
uh the way this actually works is like you know this execution payload is inside each
嗯，这实际上的工作方式就像您知道此执行有效负载在每个
consensus block so it's still just like one block but you can kind of think of it as having
共识块，所以它仍然像一个街区一样，但是您可以将其视为拥有
these two layers right and within the execution layer this is where all of our you know execution
这两个层正确，在执行层中，这是我们所有人都知道执行的地方
state lives the evm is running this is where for example like the deposit contract lives so you
状态生活EVM正在运行，例如，像存款合同一样，您
say in this block you put in your 32 ETH into the deposit contract, and there's a way now that the
在这个块中说，您将32 ETH放入存款合同中，现在有一种方法
consensus layer can basically read this execution layer, and it's just watching this deposit
共识层基本上可以读取此执行层，而只是在观看此存款
contract. So what this means is that, you know, when a new validator has put in 32 ETH,
合同。因此，这意味着，当一个新验证者投入32个ETH时，
the CL can see this, it then basically makes an entry say in the next block to add a new
CL可以看到的
validator. Okay, so there's a way for others to enter the system, there's also a way for them
验证器。好的，所以别人有一种进入系统的方法，还有一种方法
to exit, there's a consensus layer message that they would add. So let's say, I don't know,
要退出，他们会添加一条共识层消息。假设，我不知道，
let's go mini in the future. There's now, I'll start drawing big blocks for like the unified
我们将来去迷你。现在有，我将开始绘制像统一的大块
thing, but ultimately, you know, you know, this validator puts it in exit, let's say,
事情，但最终，您知道，这个验证者将其放在退出中，可以说
cause they want to stop validating the exits processed. And then ultimately, you know,
因为他们想停止验证处理的退出。最终，你知道，
some mini blocks later you end up with a withdrawal off to some other, you know, I don't know,
一些迷你块之后，您最终会退出其他一些块，您知道，我不知道，
some whatever so they get to pick you know their execution address to withdrawal two
有些
um but let's say you know we picked uh i'll just write some random hex here dead beef cafe is
嗯，但是说你知道我们选择了嗯，我会在这里写一些随机的十六进制，在这里死牛肉咖啡馆是
always fun and then how this work is once the validator is done validating um there's many
总是很有趣，然后一旦验证器完成验证，这项工作是如何的，有很多
conditions that they have to satisfy to actually exit the system but once they have then the way
他们必须满足实际退出系统的条件，但是一旦他们拥有了
to think about it is you know if they have 32 eath and maybe some rewards so let's say they're up to
想一想的是，您知道他们是否有32 eath或也许有一些奖励，所以假设他们要做
to 34th, that's withdrawn to this execution layer address.
到第34位，将其撤回到此执行层地址。
They could turn it around and then redeposit it
他们可以转过身，然后重新沉积
to the system, and however they want to do this.
到系统，但是他们想这样做。
But basically, there's now this way
但基本上，现在有这种方式
to go from the execution layer
从执行层出发
into the consensus layer and back,
进入共识层和后背，
and importantly it's permissionless.
重要的是，这是无许可的。
The only thing you really need to join the system
您真正需要加入系统的唯一一件事
is the stake, which right now is 32th.
是股份，现在是第32位。
So, okay, let me,
所以，好吧，让我，
How do I want to do this?
我要如何做？
I'll just keep going.
我会继续前进。
Okay.
好的。
So I'm now about it in the system.
所以我现在在系统中关心它。
Like, what am I going to do?
就像，我该怎么办？
Like the main thing I'm doing with respect to consensus is forming consensus.
就像我在共识方面所做的主要事情一样，是建立共识。
And so how do I do this?
那我该怎么做呢？
The way it's going to work is that as a validator, I'm going to make an attestation.
它的工作方式是，作为验证者，我将做出证明。
And if you dig into this stuff,
如果您挖掘了这些东西，
you'll see this word everywhere,
您到处都会看到这个词，
mainly because this is the core thing
主要是因为这是核心的事情
that a validator is doing.
验证者正在做。
And what it S-sensation means is it's basically saying,
Sensation的意思是基本上是在说
I'm just based on my local view,
我只是基于当地的观点，
this is the state of the chain, right, at some time.
这是一段时间的链条状态。
State of chain at,
连锁状态at
there's this notion of slot,
有这个插槽的概念，
which I'll explain in a second,
我会在一秒钟内解释
but let's just say it's slot S.
但是，我们只想说是插槽。
The way this works is that every validator, say there's a million validators on MainNet, that means that over some period of time, in these rounds of the protocol, every validator will make one attestation that is basically signing over, they make a cryptographic signature over their state of the chain.
这种工作的方法是，每个验证者都说主网上有一个百万验证器，这意味着在一定时间段内，在协议的这些一轮中，每个验证者都会做出一个基本上是签名的证明，它们会制作一个加密签名在他们的链状态上。
And if there is only one chain or like, you know, the idea is that ultimately they should all attest to the same chain.
而且，如果只有一条链，或者您知道，那么最终他们应该所有人都应该证明同一链。
And you can take all the attestations over some period of time.
您可以在一段时间内获得所有证明。
You can basically sum them all up and you end up with some notion of stake weight on some fork of the chain.
您基本上可以将它们全部概括，最终在链条的某些叉子上获得了一些损失重量的概念。
So, yeah, I'll draw this out a bit more in a second.
所以，是的，我会在一秒钟内将其提出更多。
But ultimately, the idea is that, you know, if I have my blockchain here, so this is now Ethereum.
但是最终，想法是，如果我在这里有区块链，那么现在就是以太坊。
Of course, everything has a parent chain or parent block.
当然，一切都有父链或父块。
That's nice.
那很好。
The idea is that when I go to make a new block in the chain,
这个想法是，当我去链中建立一个新块时，
every other validator is going to essentially attest, you know, to this chain.
您知道，其他所有验证者都将基本上证明这一链条。
So I'll draw like many check marks because there are many attestations.
因此，我会像许多检查标记一样绘制，因为有很多证明。
And like in particular, if there was like some other block over here
特别是，如果这里还有其他街区
that claimed the same parent, this would not be a fork in the chain, right?
那声称是同一父母，这不是链中的叉子，对吗？
Because these basically are saying relative to, you know,
因为这些基本上是在说相对于
this slot or this period of time,
这个插槽或这段时间，
then you know, the next block is either this one or this one.
然后，您知道，下一个块是这个块或一个块。
And we need to know which one, right?
我们需要知道哪一个，对吗？
This is the whole point of consensus is that if our consensus protocol is
这是共识的重点是，如果我们的共识协议是
working, we're going to pick just one, right? Because again,
工作，我们只会选择一个，对吗？因为再次
there needs to be this unique sequence.
需要有这个独特的序列。
So the attestations help us here because we can basically use the
因此，证明在这里对我们有所帮助，因为我们基本上可以使用
attestations as a way to like weight these relative chains.
证明是一种喜欢这些相对链的重量的方式。
So let's say there's like, you know, four attestations,
因此，假设有四个证明，
these like four check marks here.
这些像四个复选标记。
And let's say this block only gets like two attestations very similar to
假设这个障碍只有两个证明与
proof of work, we're going to use the attestation, the stake for each attestation, which is my
工作证明，我们将使用证明，每种证明的股份，这是我的
validator stake in the system, as this score, to score the block. So in this case, we'd have
验证器在系统中的股权，作为此分数，以评分块。因此，在这种情况下，我们有
four votes versus two, and we would say this is the head of the chain then, so as we go to put
四票与两票，我们会说这是链的负责人，所以我们去
the next block in the chain, we would vote on top of this one. I'll go into this a little bit more
链中的下一个障碍，我们将以这一障碍为基础。我会再去一点
in-depth in a little bit, but ultimately, this is kind of the idea of what these attestations
深入到一点点，但最终，这是这些证明的想法
are doing. So, I use these words a lot. So, let's actually get into some of the details here.
在做。因此，我经常使用这些单词。因此，让我们在这里介绍一些细节。
So, the way this will work is that the protocol actually has some notion of, like, you know,
因此，这种方法的工作方式是该协议实际上具有一些概念，例如，您知道，
what we call walk clock time. And what this means is that it's, like, actually the time you would
我们称之为步行时钟时间。这意味着它实际上是您会的时间
see like on a clock, right? So like, you know, if it's like, what is it like 604 UTC or something
看到时钟，对吗？所以，你知道，如果是什么，那是什么样的604 UTC或其他
right now, then you know, that's like the time. And what we're going to do is we're going to pick
现在，您知道，就像时间一样。我们要做的就是我们要选
some Genesis time. So I'll just say like, you know, T0 for the Genesis time. And the idea is
一些创世纪时间。因此，我只是说，您知道，在创世纪时间内T0。这个想法是
that this was like when the consensus protocol started. And now to like actually structure
就像共识协议启动时一样。现在喜欢真正结构
things. We're going to divide our walk clock time, again, like a normal sense of time,
事物。我们将再次将步行时钟时间分开，就像正常的时间感一样，
we're going to divide it into slots. I'll write this down. That's an important concept.
我们将将其分为插槽。我会写下来。这是一个重要的概念。
So, we have slots. The slots could be generally whatever time we want. Today,
因此，我们有插槽。插槽通常是我们想要的任何时间。今天，
they're 12 seconds. Maybe we'll talk a bit about what that means. But the idea is that
他们是12秒。也许我们会谈论这意味着什么。但是想法是
But every 12 seconds, there's a new slot, you know, T1.
但是每12秒钟，有一个新的插槽，您知道，T1。
Well, I could actually even just number these,
好吧，我实际上甚至可以编号这些，
you know, slot zero, slot one, every 12 seconds, right?
您知道，插槽零，插槽一，每12秒，对吗？
No matter what actually happens,
无论实际发生了什么，
this is just following the time out in the world.
这只是跟随世界上的时间。
And so you're always gonna have a new slot every 12 seconds.
因此，您总是每12秒就会有一个新的插槽。
Okay, so we have these slots.
好的，所以我们有这些插槽。
From here now,
现在从这里
and there's things that happen in each slot and I'll illustrate that more in a second but basically
每个插槽都会发生任何事情，我将在一秒钟内进行更多的说明，但基本上是
the idea would be that for example every slot can have a block right so I can have blocks here
例如，例如每个插槽都可以有一个块，以便我可以在这里有块
there is like you know very importantly there's the possibility that you know whatever validator
就像您非常重要的是，您有可能知道任何验证者
was supposed to propose in slot two they like missed their proposal for some reason and so
本来应该在插槽中提出的两个他们喜欢错过提议的原因，因此
this is actually just missed so I'll just do like a dotted sort of empty block here
这实际上只是错过的
The next validator would propose in slot three.
下一个验证器将在插槽三中提出。
And again, you know, so this block would have
再一次，你知道，所以这个块将有
this next parent and it would keep going.
下一位父母将继续前进。
So generally we have slots.
因此，通常我们有插槽。
The way you should think about it is that each slot
您应该考虑的方式是每个插槽
has one block.
有一个街区。
This is like the block time of Ethereum.
这就像以太坊的障碍时间。
We kind of inherited this from work where it was like
我们有点从工作中继承了这一点
targeting, maybe say like 14 seconds.
定位，也许说大约14秒。
So 12 seconds is just the number we settled on.
因此，12秒即可达到的数字。
And the idea is like, this is our smallest unit of time
这个想法就像，这是我们最小的时间单位
in the protocol where you should basically put a block
在您基本上应该放置一个块的协议中
into the chain every 12 seconds, each slot, okay.
每12秒进入链条，每个插槽都可以。
Now, what this means is that, you know, as a user,
现在，这意味着，作为用户，
let's like, you know, go to the other end of the spectrum,
让我们知道，去频谱的另一端，
back in the execution layer.
返回执行层。
When I'm a user, you know,
当我是用户时，你知道
if I make my like unit swap trade here, right?
如果我在这里进行类似的单位交易交易，对吗？
Or let's, I don't know, let's say I like broadcast it here
或者，我不知道，让我们说我喜欢在这里广播
And then what I hope, if I can preserve enough of my drawing,
然后我希望，如果我能保留足够的绘画，
what I hope is that basically a validator
我希望这基本上是一个验证者
can pick up my transaction, you know,
可以接我的交易，你知道，
and put it into, here I'll use a different color.
并将其放入，在这里我将使用其他颜色。
Here's my Uniswap trade in blue.
这是我以蓝色的unistwap贸易。
Hopefully they can pick up my transaction
希望他们能收集我的交易
along with like many others,
与许多其他人一样
and they can actually put it into the block, you know,
他们实际上可以将其放入街区中
to go into slot four.
进入插槽四。
And, you know, if you're like using, I don't know,
而且，您知道，如果您想使用，我不知道，
MetaMask to make this Uniswap trade, you know,
metamask进行这项UNISWAP交易，您知道，
There's some time before it shows up on ether scan
有一段时间才显示在以太扫描上
or if you even look at your local node, it's better.
或者，如果您甚至查看本地节点，那就更好了。
But ultimately, there's some time
但最终有一段时间
before you actually get the transaction on chain.
在您实际获得链上的交易之前。
And that's because of the slot time.
那是因为插槽时间。
You don't have a new block until somewhere
直到某个地方，您都没有新的街区
between zero and 12 seconds,
在零到12秒之间，
depending on when you actually broadcast
取决于您何时广播
this original transaction.
这项原始交易。
Okay.
好的。
So, that's kind of a feel for sort of this
所以，这是一种感觉
heartbeat of the protocol and how things might line up
协议的心跳以及事情如何排队
with you making transactions.
与您进行交易。
That's the execution layer.
那是执行层。
Separately, there's a lot of machinery
单独有很多机械
that consists of this layer.
由此层组成。
And in particular, so here's one thing, these attestations.
特别是，这是一件事，这些证明。
The idea again is that for every slot,
再次想法是，对于每个插槽，
let me go back to my other color.
让我回到另一种颜色。
So for every slot, you're gonna have some attestations.
因此，对于每个插槽，您都会有一些证明。
So I don't know, let's say attestation from validator 123,
所以我不知道，假设验证者123的证明，
we go into this block, but also attestation 456.
我们进入这个街区，但也证明了456。
And in general, you're gonna have like many attestations
总的来说，您将有很多证明
per block, and then separately,
每个块，然后单独
you're gonna have more for the next block, right?
您将为下一个区块有更多的东西，对吗？
So I don't know.
所以我不知道。
Pick your favorite validator indices,
选择您喜欢的验证器索引，
but ultimately, validators make attestations,
但最终，验证者做出证明，
the idea is that it should go to the next block.
这个想法是它应该转到下一个块。
And in particular, the way this works
特别是，这是有效的方式
is that for each of these blocks,
是每个块中的每个块
there's gonna be like a unique state
会有一个独特的状态
of the chain they attest to, or that they commit to rather,
他们证明的链，或者他们致力于
and validators then, when they make these attestations,
然后验证者，当他们做出这些证明时，
they basically just look at this block
他们基本上只是看这个块
So it's at the station say from value or one, two, three,
因此，在车站说，从价值或一个，两个，三，三，
they're gonna look at the state of the chain.
他们会看链的状态。
They're gonna say, wow, okay.
他们会说，哇，好吧。
So it really works is that in this slot,
所以它确实有效的是，在这个插槽中，
they would actually look at say their prior slots,
他们实际上会说他们先前的老虎机，
which in this case would even take you back to this block.
在这种情况下，这甚至将带您回到这个块。
But ultimately you're gonna look at the latest state
但是最终您要看最新状态
of the chain and they would sign over,
链条，他们会签约，
hey, I think the current block is this one
嘿，我认为当前的街区是这个
that then would get included.
那将被包括在内。
Okay, I've run a little out of sync here.
好吧，我在这里跑了一点同步。
Sorry about that.
对此很抱歉。
Let me simplify this a bit.
让我简化一点。
Let me actually just do this.
我实际上就是这样做。
So now we're going to zoom in actually into one slot.
因此，现在我们将真正放大一个插槽。
So let's say we'll take slot three as our example.
假设我们将以三个插槽为例。
The way this works is that,
这个方法是，
so this is like, you know, t equals zero, t equals 12.
因此，这就像t等于零，t等于12。
And again, this is like slot three.
再说一次，这就像插槽三。
over here is like slot four.
在这里就像插槽四。
So we're just looking at one slot now.
因此，我们现在只是在看一个插槽。
The way this would work is that the validator for slot three,
这将使用的方式是，插槽三的验证器，
they're gonna make this block here,
他们要在这里做这个街区，
and they should release near the start of the slot.
他们应该在插槽开始时释放。
This is gonna have attestations from the previous slot,
这将从上一个插槽中得到证明，
let's say all of my transactions,
假设我的所有交易，
like my unit swap trades and whatever,
就像我的单位交易交易等等一样，
all the stuff that needs to go into the xblock
所有需要进入Xblock的东西
is gonna be here.
会在这里。
The way this works is then at like t equals four,
然后，这种工作的方式与四个相等，
just to divide this slot up into thirds, or thirds rather.
只是将这个插槽分为三分之二或三分之二。
Any validator who's assigned to test in slot three,
任何分配在插槽中测试的验证者，
they're going to say,
他们要说的
hey, I'm gonna make an attestation.
嘿，我要认证。
Let's say the block root, as we call them here,
假设我们在这里称呼它们的块根，
is like ABD.
就像ABD。
They're gonna say my attestation.
他们会说我的证明。
So let's, we're looking at validator one, two, three again.
因此，让我们再次研究验证者一，两个，三个。
Their attestation's gonna say, yeah,
他们的证明会说，是的，
my state of the chain is ABD, whatever the rest of the hash is. They're going to broadcast their
我的链条状态是ABD，无论其余的哈希是什么。他们将播放他们的
attestation. There are different actors who then basically have the next four seconds to aggregate
证明。有不同的演员基本上有接下来的四秒钟来汇总
them into like a smaller package to go on chain. And the idea is that ultimately this attestation
它们像一个较小的包装中，可以沿着链条上进行。这个想法是最终这种证明
ends up in the next slot, right? So now we have the next block, which has, you know, again,
最终进入下一个插槽，对吗？因此，现在我们有了下一个块，您再次知道，
like our unit swap transactions
像我们的单位交易交易
or whatever new execution state there is,
或任何新的执行状态，
but then it also should include this attestation.
但是，它也应包括此证明。
Then you just get the blocks from the network.
然后，您只需从网络中获得块即可。
You can then count these attestations as they come in
然后，您可以计算出这些证明
and they can tell you things like,
他们可以告诉你类似的事情
yes, a majority of the batter set
是的，大多数击球手套装
thought that this was actually the block in slot three.
认为这实际上是插槽三的块。
Okay.
好的。
So this is at the slot level.
因此，这是在插槽级别。
There's another notion that
还有另一个观念
okay um a little short on time but that's my problem so there's another notion which is uh
好的，嗯，时间短一点，但这是我的问题，所以还有另一个概念
an epoch so the way to think about epochs is that there's some number of slots
一个时代，所以思考时期的方法是有一些插槽
um and on main net for example there's 32 slots per epoch and the reason we do this
嗯，在主网上，每个时期有32个插槽，而我们这样做的原因
is that we basically went to like um there's like a bunch of consensus processing that is relatively
是我们基本上去喜欢um，就像一堆共识处理相对较好
heavy and so we want to batch it so it only happens every so often rather than every slot
沉重，所以我们想批处理它，以便它只会经常发生，而不是每个插槽
so the way i think about this is that you know here's our 32 slots
所以我对此的看法是，您知道这是我们的32个插槽
i didn't draw 32 but you get the picture um you know this is like
我没有画32，但是你得到图片，你知道这就像
you know we'll just start at genesis so zero one two three dot dot dot dot and this is you
您知道我们只是从创世记开始，所以零一两个三点点点点，这就是你
This would be slot 30 and 31.
这将是插槽30和31。
So these are zero indexed, you get to 32 slots for epoch.
因此，这些索引为零，您可以到32个时段的插槽。
And this then would be epoch,
那将是时代，
since we started at Genesis, epoch zero.
自从我们从创世纪开始时，时代零。
The way you should think about this is, again,
您应该考虑的方式再次是
it keeps going just based on time.
它一直基于时间。
You're now in epoch one here, and there's more slots.
您现在在一个时代的一个时代，还有更多的位置。
So this is now slot 32, all the way up to the next multiple,
因此，现在是插槽32，一直到下一个多个多个多个插槽，
so you'd end up at slot 63.
因此，您最终会在63个插槽中。
you then go to epoch two, slot 64, hopefully that's clear.
然后，您去了两个时期，插槽64，希望这很清楚。
And the idea is, one thing you're gonna do for example,
这个想法是，你要做的一件事，例如
is like if anyone's trying to enter x into batter set,
就像有人试图将X输入击球设置一样，
you're gonna do that at this epoch boundary
你要在这个时代的边界上做到这一点
where you do all this heavier processing.
在哪里进行所有这些较重的处理。
I don't know what that was.
我不知道那是什么。
Oh, I just deleted something.
哦，我只是删除了一些东西。
Okay, right, so you are gonna do this epoch processing
好吧，对，所以你要进行这个时代的处理
and then the idea is like, you know, there's, sorry,
然后这个想法就像，你知道，对不起，
There's blocks here, right?
这里有街区，对吗？
So let's say ideally you have like 32 blocks, great.
因此，理想情况下，您有32个街区，很棒。
And as you go here,
当你去这里时
not only are you gonna do like the normal processing,
您不仅会喜欢普通处理，而且
but you're also gonna say things like, okay,
但是你也会说，好吧，
if someone got slashed
如果有人被砍了
or if there are any penalties or rewards,
或者如果有任何处罚或奖励，
we're gonna basically like hand these out
我们基本上会喜欢把这些
and update the consistent state at this boundary.
并在此边界更新一致的状态。
Okay, so we have slots, we have epochs,
好吧，所以我们有老虎机，我们有时代，
And yeah, okay.
是的，好的。
So like an important thing to realize is that,
如此重要的是，要认识到的是，
so we have like the whole Valider set here.
因此，我们喜欢这里的整个Valider。
So I don't know Valider zero, Valider one, you know,
所以我不知道Valider Zero，Valider One，您知道，
for example, MainNet up to like, you know,
例如，mainnet要喜欢，你知道，
something like that, almost, you know,
像这样的东西，几乎，你知道，
the millionth Validator.
百万验证者。
And the idea is that they are randomly shuffled
这个想法是他们被随机改组
every epoch into these committees.
每个时期都进入这些委员会。
And what that would look like is that for a given epoch,
看起来是，对于给定的时代，
so here's our slots in the epoch,
所以这是我们在时代的老虎机，
let's say for example, there's like 100 validators.
例如，例如，有100个验证者。
Well, yeah, maybe I'll try to make this a little bit easier.
好吧，是的，也许我会尽力使它更轻松一些。
So there's 32 slots.
所以有32个插槽。
Let's just say there's 320 validators.
假设有320个验证器。
So if there's 32 slots,
因此，如果有32个插槽，
that's something like 10 validators per slot, right?
那是每个插槽的10个验证者，对吗？
And the idea is like the 10 validators per the,
这个想法就像每个验证者一样，
out of the entire set, which is now 320,
在整个集合中，现在是320
you're gonna randomly shuffle them and put 10 validators.
您将随机洗牌，并放10个验证器。
Those look like blocks.
这些看起来像块。
Let me do something differently.
让我做一些不同的事情。
So one, two, three, validator, four, five, six.
因此，一个，两个，三个，验证者，四个，五，六。
Again, the idea is that there are like 10 validators here,
同样，这个想法是这里有10个验证器，
and this is like a pretty important invariance
这就像一个非常重要的不变性
is that a validator makes one S station per epoch.
是一个验证器每个时期的一个S站。
The exact slot data that ends is determined by the protocol.
结束的确切插槽数据由协议确定。
There's this notion of like the Randow,
有这样的想法，
which is the way this works
这是这种工作的方式
is that when I go to put a block in the chain,
是当我去链中放一个块时，
maybe I'll go back here.
也许我会回到这里。
Yeah, so as I go to put the block in the chain,
是的，所以当我要把块放在链中时，
I basically put some local randomness and every block.
我基本上放了一些局部随机性和每个块。
So we'll say like, you know, R0, R1, R2,
所以我们会说，您知道，R0，R1，R2，
you basically just like mix them all together
您基本上就像将它们混合在一起
in a particular way.
以特殊的方式。
And the idea then is that there's this notion of randomness
然后的想法是，存在这种随机性的概念
that you can then use to do the shuffling,
然后您可以用来进行洗牌，
to decide then say for the next epoch,
为了决定下一个时代，
what this validator shuffling should be.
这个验证者的改组应该是什么。
Validers then make one at station per each epoch,
有效器然后每个时期的车站制作一个，
again assigned to like some particular slot.
再次分配给一些特定的插槽。
So, you know, now there's like two, two, two, one, nine, six.
因此，您知道，现在有两个，两个，两个，一个，九，六。
And yeah, so similarly you end up with all of them
是的，同样，您最终都会得到所有人
in a unique slot.
在一个独特的插槽中。
And this then tells you that,
然后这告诉你，
did I,
我了吗，
yeah, maybe I'll just do this again.
是的，也许我会再做一次。
So basically it tells you that,
因此，基本上告诉您，
uh we're looking at slots now
嗯，我们现在正在寻找老虎机
um well here this will be clear if there's just one so basically now you know we're at like uh
嗯，这里很清楚，如果只有一个，那么现在您就知道我们在
this is like slot 23 you know this is at t equals zero in the slot t equals 12 based on my view of
这就像插槽23，您知道这在插槽t中等于12等于我的观点
the chain i'm going to have some assignment and let's say again our lucky validator 123 is assigned
我将要进行一些任务的链条，然后再说一次我们的幸运验证者123
in slot 23 to attest uh when they see this block they then make their attestation
在插槽23中，以证明他们看到这个块时，他们就会证明
and this would then ultimately get into the next block okay so
然后这最终将进入下一个障碍，所以
okay let me then touch now on consensus um and that will actually probably put us at time
好吧，让我现在触摸共识，这实际上可能会让我们到达
all right i got a couple questions for you before we move on okay um yeah great got one question is
好吧，我在我们继续前进之前就收到了几个问题，好吧，嗯，很棒的问题是
Can you elaborate it on the time concept in proof of stake?
您能否详细说明它的时间概念以证明股份？
Like why 12 seconds?
喜欢为什么12秒？
How do they get split?
他们如何分裂？
Why are the 32 slots per epoch, et cetera?
为什么每个时代的32个插槽等等？
Right.
正确的。
So the 12 seconds is like kind of arbitrary.
因此，12秒就像是任意的。
It was inspired by the work walk time, which was like on average
它的灵感来自工作时间，这平均就像
about 14 seconds.
大约14秒。
So we just went for something a similar time.
所以我们只是去了类似的时间。
The the number is kind of arbitrary.
这个数字是任意的。
it could be smaller or longer.
它可能更小或更长。
If it's smaller, then basically
如果较小，那么基本上
it becomes harder to follow the chain.
遵循链条变得更加困难。
Maybe a simpler way to think
也许是一种更简单的思考方式
about it first is the longer the slot,
首先是插槽的时间越长，
it gives you more time to pass
它给您更多的时间通过
the blocks, pass the attestations, figure out
块，通过证明，弄清楚
which attestations to go into the next block and do
哪些证明可以进入下一个区块并做
all this. Again, now there's this trade-off
所有这些。再次，现在有这种权衡
between how quickly the
在多快的速度之间
protocol can progress
协议可以进展
and the slot time.
和插槽时间。
12 seconds is what we have today.
我们今天拥有12秒。
Some people argue
有人争论
for shortening the slot time, because it means, for example, it's execution state would evolve
为了缩短插槽时间，因为它意味着它的执行状态将进化
more frequently. People also talk about lengthening slot time, because there's other
更频繁。人们还谈论延长插槽时间，因为还有其他
consensus upgrades we're thinking about where it actually makes more sense to have a longer slot
共识升级，我们正在考虑拥有更长插槽的实际情况更有意义
time to do more stuff every period of time. What was the other question?
是时候在每个时间段内做更多的事情了。另一个问题是什么？
Can you talk a bit about the randomness, about the brand dial,
您能谈谈随机性，品牌表盘吗？
and how the validators are shuffled randomly or uh right okay yeah so
以及验证者如何随机洗牌或呃，好吧，是的
uh okay yeah we can still see this so the idea here is that um right so there's one i mean i
好吧，是的，我们仍然可以看到这个，所以这里的想法是对的，所以我的意思是我
guess this is another important invariance there's one proposer per slot and kind of like i was
猜猜这是另一个重要的不变性，每个插槽有一个建议者，就像我一样
alluding to um you know the proposer could like miss their slots in which case there just isn't
暗示嗯，你知道提议者可能会想念他们的老虎机，在这种情况下不是
into block for that slot.
进入该插槽的块。
But generally, especially on main net,
但是通常，尤其是在主要网上，
people are incentivized to participate
人们被激励参加
and so they do their job well.
因此，他们做得很好。
And so you can imagine then that like every slot
因此，您可以想象，就像每个插槽一样
ends up with a block.
最终有一个块。
Okay.
好的。
And the way to think about this is that
考虑到这一点的方法是
I don't know, when I go to propose,
我不知道，当我去提议时，
let's say I'm Validator, I don't know, 27.
假设我是验证者，我不知道，27。
As I go to propose, then I'm gonna also
当我提出建议时，我也会
include some randomness, which, you know,
包括一些随机性，您知道，
there's some details where you can go look at it.
有一些细节，您可以去看它。
This is a spec essentially the way to think about it is
这本质上是思考的规格是
I'm gonna take like my slot number.
我会像我的老虎机号码一样。
So say this is like, I don't know, slot 45,000.
所以说这就像我不知道，插槽45,000。
I'm gonna basically like take this number,
我基本上会喜欢这个号码，
maybe hash it some other things.
也许还有其他事情。
And ultimately I'm gonna get like a seed value
最终我会变得像种子价值
that I'm gonna sign over just with
我要和
like my validator private key.
像我的验证器私钥一样。
And the way this works is that the signature
这项工作的方式是签名
up being like a you know pseudo random value um so i'm gonna get like some randomness um
像一个你知道的伪随机价值嗯，我会变得像随机性一样
we'll just call it r um then basically i mean again these are like very low level details but
我们只是称其为r um，然后我的意思是，这些都是非常低的详细信息，但是
you take this readiness which is the signature um you're going to hash that to get like down to 32
您准备了这种准备，这是您要降低到32的签名
bytes again which should be pseudo random um within the consistent state itself so for each
再次在一致的状态本身内再次是伪随机的字节
of these blocks right we're going to mix in each new randall into the state and what that means is
在这些块中，我们将在每个新的兰德尔中混合到州，这是什么意思
that there's going to be some like current value from this having happened in the past and then
从过去发生的情况下，这将有一些当前价值，然后
for each block i'm just going to take whatever my random contribution was and i'm going to mix it in
对于每个块
to what's already there so the way to think about this is that basically there's like um so for
对于已经存在的事情，考虑到这一点的方法是基本上有UM So
every block right the blocks can have some effect there's now like a consensus state it will say as
每个块正确的块都可以产生一定的效果，现在有一个共识状态，它将说为
S-45K, S-45,001.
S-45K，S-45,001。
Hopefully you get the idea.
希望你明白这个主意。
But basically each block is going to make a new state.
但是基本上每个块都将建立一个新状态。
And then the idea is that within this beacon state,
然后的想法是，在这个信标状态中，
yeah, I'm not sure how awful this will be,
是的，我不确定这会多么糟糕，
but just imagine there's some state over here
但是试想一下这里有一些状态
as this triangle.
作为三角形。
There's going to be like some ran down value.
会有一些价值。
Again, we'll just call it R0.
同样，我们将其称为R0。
When I go to apply, say now my block,
当我去申请时，说我的障碍，
let's say I'm going to apply, you know, block 45,001.
假设我将申请45,001块。
There's going to be, like, some unique random for the proposer,
对于提议者来说，会有一些独特的随机
which I'm calling R prime.
我称之为R Prime。
We're going to combine these two and get back some, like, new value R1.
我们将结合这两个并恢复一些新值R1。
And this happens for each block.
每个块都会发生这种情况。
And the idea then is that you should have some, like, random value
然后的想法是，您应该有一些，例如随机价值
that each proposer is updating as they go.
每个提议者都在更新。
and then separately you get to this notion of shuffling so the way this works now is like um
然后单独进入这种改组的概念，所以现在的工作方式就像UM
there's a notion of look ahead just so people know and they have some time to like get ready to
有一个未来的想法，只是让人们知道，他们有一些时间喜欢做好准备
say make their attestation or propose their block but the way to think about this is like let's say
说出他们的证明或提出障碍，但考虑到这一点的方式就像是说
this is like epoch one two three epoch one two four epoch one two five so basically
这就像一个时代一个两个三个时代一个两个时代一个两个四个时期一两个五个五个五个五个五个五个五
the way this works is that at the end of this epoch, so like whatever this final block is,
这种工作的方式是，在这个时期的结尾，就像最终区块一样，
you know, so there's many blocks here in this epoch, great, you're going to end up with some,
你知道，所以这个时代有很多街区，太好了，你最终会得到一些，
you know, unique random value, we'll call it like r123. What that then is going to do
您知道，独特的随机值，我们将其称为R123。那将要做什么
is basically tell you, okay, so it's a little backwards here, because of whether the lookahead
基本上是告诉你，好吧，所以这里有点倒退，因为lookahead是否
works let's instead say we're going into like this epoch the way this works is that we're
作品让我们说我们像这样的时代一样，就像我们一样
going to basically uh look back at the randomness we made here and that's going to then basically
基本上要回顾我们在这里做出的随机性，这基本上是
tell us the the shufflings for say like the next two epochs hopefully that's clear this
告诉我们像接下来的两个时代那样说的，希望这很清楚
look ahead thing's a little confusing but basically the idea is that um at some you
向前看，事情有点令人困惑，但基本上的想法是嗯
you know, at some point in time, say like here,
你知道，在某个时间点，像这里一样
we're gonna look at the beacon state,
我们要看标准州，
which I guess I started drawing this triangles.
我想我开始绘制这三角形。
We're gonna look at the beacon state.
我们要看一下信标国家。
There's gonna be some random value,
会有一些随机价值，
again, it's called R.
同样，它叫R。
And the idea then is like this R is an input to like say,
然后，这个想法就像是这样说的输入，
some code reruns and shuffle function,
某些代码重播和洗牌功能，
which takes like the entire validator set,
就像整个验证器集一样
it's gonna take R and you know, for example,
它将需要r，例如，你知道
without the stations, like the committee size or something,
没有电台，例如委员会规模或其他东西，
it's then gonna take all of the validators.
然后，它将带走所有验证者。
So, you know, again, on main net,
因此，您再次知道，在主要网上
this is like almost a million it's gonna say, okay,
这就像它要说的近一百万，好的，
we actually wanna break them up into like this number
实际上，我们想将它们像这个数字一样分解成
of committees per epoch.
每个时期委员会的委员会。
So, you know, let's say it's like whatever number this is,
因此，您知道，假设它就像是什么数字，
where they're gonna shuffle them.
他们会在哪里洗牌。
So, okay, the way we started it was the whole list, right?
所以，好的，我们开始的方式是整个列表，对吗？
So just counting the validators,
因此，仅计算验证器，
that are zero, one, two, three, you know,
零，一，两个，三，你知道，
all the way up to say like, you know, nine, nine, six,
一直以来说，你知道，九，九，六，
whatever, just under a million,
无论如何，不​​到一百万，
we're then gonna use this randomness here to shuffle these.
然后，我们将在这里使用这种随机性来洗牌。
And so then what that means is that we're gonna end up
那就意味着我们最终会
with like a shuffled set,
像洗牌一样，
say, you know, Validator 0 goes over to like,
说，您知道，验证器0逐渐to，
I don't know, say here, right?
我不知道，在这里说，对吗？
So you end up with like Validator 0 here,
因此，您最终在此处获得类似验证器0，
and now this is like 45,
现在这就像45岁，
nine, five, six,
九，五，六，
Validator 12, Validator 0, Validator 3,
验证器12，验证器0，验证器3，
And the idea is they get shuffled, right?
他们的想法是被改组了，对吗？
In some random way, then, you know,
然后，您知道，以某种随机的方式
if we wanna break this up in that station committees,
如果我们想在那个车站委员会中分解它，
you just then basically like batch them, right?
那时，您基本上喜欢批处理，对吗？
And then this tells you, you know, in the next e-talk,
然后，这告诉您，在下一个电子通话中，
you end up with like, okay, I'm in this first committee,
您最终会像，好吧，我是第一个委员会的
which is in say the first slot.
这是第一个插槽。
And then I end up in the next committee,
然后我最终加入下一个委员会，
which is in the next slot, something like this.
在下一个插槽中，类似。
Hopefully that was helpful.
希望这很有帮助。
I do want to, we just have a few minutes, so I do want to like, explain a bit more about
我确实想，我们只有几分钟，所以我想喜欢，解释更多有关
ConsenSys and how this works.
共识以及这是如何工作的。
And yeah, unfortunately, there's actually a lot to say.
是的，不幸的是，实际上有很多话要说。
So yeah, we won't necessarily get to everything today.
所以，是的，我们今天不一定要涉足一切。
But hopefully I've piqued your interest.
但希望我已经激发了您的兴趣。
And yeah, you can dig in more.
是的，您可以挖掘更多。
So let's zoom out again, to our notion of the Ethereum chain.
因此，让我们再次放大以太坊链的概念。
To close the picture on consensus, right.
要关闭共识时的图片。
So we have, again, let's think about epochs.
因此，我们再次考虑一下时代。
So like epoch, I don't know, one, two, three,
因此，就像时代一样，我不知道，一个，两个，三，
one, two, four, one, two, five, one, two, six,
一，两个，二，四，二，五，一，二，六，
maybe something like this.
也许是这样的。
And we're gonna start with some block, you know,
我们将从一些街区开始
this could even be like the nearsighted block
这甚至可能就像近视块
or whatever it, whatever.
无论如何，无论如何。
Well, okay, this is where it starts to get confusing.
好吧，好吧，这是它开始变得令人困惑的地方。
it confusing. So there's blocks here now, because this was an epoch. These are now the slots,
令人困惑。所以现在这里有街区，因为这是一个时代。这些现在是插槽，
right? And again, sorry if this is confusing, but basically it's just like, there's a new slot
正确的？再说一次，很抱歉，如果这令人困惑，但基本上就像是一个新的插槽
every 12 seconds. Just like that. That's just how it works. Maybe you could like not have a block
每12秒一次。就是这样。这就是它的工作方式。也许您可能没有一个街区
either way um you have these blocks and uh these blocks now have attestations
无论哪种方式，您都有这些块，并且这些块现在有证明
so yeah that's maybe a little cramped but basically the idea is that you know if we have
是的，这可能有点局促，但基本上是您知道我们是否有
more blocks here then they're going to basically have attestations to you know the state of the
这里有更多块，然后他们将基本上证明您知道
chain and i guess i'll just switch to like check marks now and you know you might have like quite
链，我想我现在就切换到喜欢的复选标记，你知道你可能很喜欢
it but ultimately um the way to think about this now is with respect to consensus and this notion
它，但现在最终思考这个方法是关于共识和这个概念的
of like finality that we care about this is like the whole thing that we're trying to do with proof
我们关心的最终结局就像我们试图用证据做的整个事情
of state consensus is to get to the social finality and when something's final it means it
国家共识是要达到社会终结性，而当某事的最终结果意味着它
basically will never change and i'll kind of explain a bit more what that means um the way to
基本上永远不会改变，我会再解释一下，这意味着什么
think about it is that uh we're now going to work kind of in terms of uh we call them like epoch
考虑一下是，我们现在将以嗯，我们称它们为时代
boundary blocks but the way to think about it is just like the first block in an epoch it's
边界区块，但思考的方式就像一个时代中的第一个街区一样
just going to stand in as like a representative for each epoch and if you think about it because
只是像每个时期一样像代表一样站在里面，如果您考虑一下，因为
everything is cryptographically linked via the parent hash you know like if i somehow like have
一切都通过您知道的父母哈希链接，就像我以某种方式一样
the validators all vote um or maybe this is a better example here if i have them like you know
验证者全部投票，或者这是一个更好的例子，如果我像您所知道的那样拥有它们
if even though these like these attestations here right they are implicitly attesting to like this
即使这些像这些证明在这里正确
being the block of the beginning of this epoch again because these all have parent hashes
再次成为这个时代开始的街区，因为所有这些都有父母的哈希
and yeah sorry there's so many arrows but the point i'm trying to make is that you can now
是的，对不起，有很多箭头，但我要提出的重点是您现在可以
kind of zoom out and you can now say okay um for this epoch there's like this block
有点放大，您现在可以说好嗯，为这个时代有这个块
this block and this block this block okay and you know the direct parent hash is from block to block
这个块和此块这个块还可以，您知道直接的父母哈希是从块到块
but the way to think about it is there's kind of these like linkages you can make
但是思考的方法是，您可以建立这些喜欢的联系
between each epoch, right?
在每个时期之间，对吗？
And the way this is going to work is that
这将如何工作的方式是
based on the attestations we get in a given epoch,
根据我们在给定时期获得的证明，
they're going to have this notion of justification.
他们将有这样的理由。
Let me actually just write that down.
实际上，让我写下来。
This is a key concept.
这是一个关键概念。
What justification means is, again, this BFT concept
合理的含义是这个BFT概念
that, you know, at least two-thirds of the validators
您知道，至少有三分之二的验证者
have attested to a given block.
已经证明了给定的块。
So, you know, you could, like, count all of the attestations here,
因此，您知道，您可以像在这里计算所有证明，
and they would ultimately, if you reach this threshold,
如果您达到这个门槛，他们最终将
then they would be justifying, you know, this block, right?
然后，他们会为这个障碍做出合理的理由，对吗？
So you have justification.
所以你有理由。
And what this kind of looks like then is that you end up with, you know,
那时的这种外观是您最终得到的，您知道，
a block tree that kind of looks like, you know, this picture,
一棵块树，看起来像这张照片，
where you then have like, yeah, maybe I should use,
然后，您喜欢的地方，是的，也许我应该使用，
I guess I'll use blue or something.
我想我会使用蓝色或其他东西。
That would be nice.
那会很好。
You can end up like justifying with respect to like one epoch,
您最终可以像一个时代一样辩解，
the previous epoch.
以前的时代。
So then you get these things.
因此，您会得到这些东西。
And now when these are blue arrows,
现在，当这些是蓝色箭头时，
what I'm trying to communicate is like, you know,
我想传达的是，你知道，
you have like at least two thirds of attestations,
您拥有至少三分之二的证明，
all referencing directly or indirectly, you know, these blocks here.
所有这些都直接或间接地引用这些块。
Okay.
好的。
So that's justification.
这就是理由。
And in particular, well, yeah, I think I'll talk about,
尤其是，是的，我想我会谈论的，
it just splits in a second,
它只是在一秒钟内分裂
but in particular, what we wanna get to
但特别是，我们想达到的目标
is this notion of finality.
这是最终的概念。
And finality here means that, again,
而且最终性意味着再次
it looks like we're kind of at time,
看来我们有点时候
so I'll just kind of be brief here,
所以我在这里很简短，
but ultimately the idea is that if I, let's see,
但最终的想法是，如果我，让我们看看，
Like, let's see if, sorry,
就像，让我们看看是否，对不起，
if I justify a justified block,
如果我证明合理的块，
then, and I'll call it b,
然后，我称它为B，
if I justify a justify block b, then b is finalized.
如果我证明是合理的B块B，则B将最终确定。
And in this case, we'll call this b
在这种情况下，我们将其称为b
because what happened is,
因为发生的事情是
ah, you can't see my hands, that's too bad.
啊，你看不到我的手，太糟糕了。
But basically before we had these votes come in,
但是基本上，在我们获得这些选票之前，
we had justified B, basically,
我们基本上证明了b是合理的
and this epoch, we had justified B,
这个时代，我们证明了b，
and then we came along and we justified this block,
然后我们来了，我们证明了这个障碍，
I don't know, I'll call it C, we justified C,
我不知道，我称其为c，我们证明了C，
because we justified
因为我们有理由
a block that had been justified, namely B,
一个有理由的块，即B，
B is now final.
B现在是决赛。
And this is like the whole point of what we're trying to do
这就像我们要做的事情的重点
is get to this notion of finality.
要达到这个结局的概念。
And let's see what to say here.
让我们看看这里该说些什么。
I guess I'll just kind of explain what we mean here.
我想我会在这里解释我们的意思。
What we mean here is that it's final
我们的意思是最终
because if we had then tried to attest,
因为如果我们试图证明，
like if we had tried to justify a different block,
就像我们试图证明另一个块是合理的一样，
let me do this.
让我这样做。
So sure, let's do something like this.
所以当然，让我们做这样的事情。
Okay.
好的。
Let me just draw these arrows.
让我画这些箭。
So right.
没错。
There's again this notion of slashing.
再次有这种削减的概念。
And for example, attesting to two conflicting blocks here, this would be slashable.
例如，在这里证明两个相互矛盾的块，这将是可砍的。
And then what this means is that you can't get in a situation where you've finalized
然后这意味着您无法在最终确定的情况下获得
two different histories.
两个不同的历史。
say the top and the bottom, because if you do, then what would happen is say all the attestations
说顶部和底部，因为如果您这样做，那将发生的是说所有证明
that tried to finalize this block, let's say, on this chain, they would be in conflict with
试图最终确定这个区块，可以说，在这链上，它们将与
the top chain, and you could then basically put these attestations as proof of misbehavior
顶级链条，然后您基本上可以将这些证明作为行为不当的证明
into the top chain. You would slash these validators, and you can't get to this situation
进入顶链。您将削减这些验证器，而您无法遇到这种情况
where you finalize two conflicting histories
您最终确定了两个相互矛盾的历史
without it being slashable.
没有它是可砍的。
And so this is what we mean by final.
因此，这就是我们最终的意思。
You have this notion of like economic finality
您有这样的经济终结概念
that does what we want.
那做我们想要的。
Okay, yeah, sorry, I think we're at time,
好吧，是的，对不起，我想我们是时候了，
but I can stay for some questions.
但是我可以留下一些问题。
And yeah, sorry, we ran over.
是的，对不起，我们跑了。
Thanks, Alex, no problem on going over.
谢谢，亚历克斯，没问题。
Um, one question, uh, can you talk a little bit about, uh, Gaspar in the context of, of
嗯，一个问题，嗯，你能谈谈，呃，在
finalization and finding the canonical chain?
最终确定并找到规范链？
Right.
正确的。
So, so Gaspar is like our particular, like instantiation of this protocol that I've been
因此，因此Gaspar就像我们的特殊事物一样，就像我去过的协议的实例化
trying to lay out.
试图布置。
Um, and again, this is where it starts to get a little, a little complex, but basically
嗯，再一次，它开始变得有些复杂，但基本上是
there's almost two views.
有近两个观点。
There's like the epoch level view, which is kind of what I was just talking about, where it's like you have blocks that are kind of representing like, you know, this like epoch level thing.
就像时代级别的视图一样，这就是我刚刚在谈论的内容，就像您的块一样代表，就像时代级别一样。
But then within each epoch, right, you're still going to have, let's see if I can draw this.
但是，在每个时期内，您仍然会有，让我们看看我是否可以绘制它。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'll just do this, for example.
例如，我只是这样做。
You're still going to have all the other blocks.
您仍然将拥有所有其他块。
And so, like, a really cool thing about Ethereum is we have this notion of dynamic availability.
因此，就像以太坊的一件非常酷的事情是，我们有这种动态可用性的概念。
And the idea here is that basically you can keep adding to the chain.
这里的想法是，基本上您可以继续添加到链条中。
So let's say this is out of the chain.
因此，假设这是链条。
You can keep adding to the head of the chain kind of separately from this finality process.
您可以不断地添加到与此最终过程中分开的链条的头部。
So, like, even if finality for some reason, like, let's say there's, like, a bunch of others go offline and they can't get their attestations on chain.
因此，就像，即使出于某种原因的结局，例如，例如，还有一堆其他人离线，他们无法获得链条的证明。
chain, then finality, we might say that we've only finalized this block B or this epoch
链条，然后是最终性，我们可能会说我们只完成了这个块B或这个时代
B, the chain can still go on.
B，连锁店仍然可以继续。
You can keep adding to the head of the chain.
您可以继续添加到链的头部。
And so then what that means is that this finality process is kind of trailing the actual blockchain.
因此，这意味着这个终结过程有点落后于实际区块链。
And so then if you go to the head of the chain, say here, and I will zoom in now.
因此，如果您走到链条的头部，请在这里说，我现在将放大。
So let's say this is like epoch, I don't know, E minus one.
假设这就像时代，我不知道，e减。
And so now we're here, and this is now, these are slots.
因此，现在我们在这里，现在是插槽。
So you still now have blocks in the block tree, meaning a proposer can go, let's say
因此，您现在仍然有块树中的块，这意味着提议者可以走
this was a missed slot, this proposer proposes here, the next proposer, let's say they propose
这位提议者在这里提议，这是一个错过的插槽，下一个提议者，假设他们提出了
to say, you know, even back here.
要说，你知道，甚至回到这里。
And now what you have in general
现在你一般拥有的
is you now have this same block tree
您现在有同一块树吗
where you still need to make this consensus inference,
您仍然需要在哪里进行共识推断，
meaning like, is this the head of the chain
意思是，这是链的头
or is this the head of the chain?
还是这是链的头？
And again, we use the attestations for this.
同样，我们对此进行了证明。
As these attestations in each block are coming in,
随着每个块中的这些证明都进入，
you know, they're gonna attest to one block or the other,
你知道，他们会证明一个街区或另一个街区，
and that's gonna say give, you know,
这就是要说的，你知道，
some weight of like, you know,
你知道的一定重量
a hundred ETH attesting here
一百个伦理在这里证明
versus like, you know, a thousand ETH attesting here.
相对于您知道的，在这里证明了一千个。
And in general, then we have this other algorithm,
总的来说，我们还有其他算法，
LMD ghost, you might've heard of it, I'll write it down.
LMD Ghost，您可能已经听说过，我将其写下来。
But it works very much like even where we saw it before
但是它的工作非常类似于我们以前看到的地方
where you're gonna say, start from like some head we know,
你要说的话，从我们知道的一个头开始，
and then just basically like,
然后基本上喜欢，
this G here is like greedy.
这里的g就像贪婪。
So basically, find the one with the most stake weight
因此，基本上，找到最大的股份
going off the attestations.
退出证明。
And so when we say Gaspar, this is really what we mean
因此，当我们说Gaspar时，这确实是我们的意思
is there's this like FFG friendly finality gadget.
有像FFG友好的终结小工具一样。
It's not super important what the acronym stands for,
首字母缩写词的代表并不重要，
but ultimately this like epoch level process
但最终这类时期的过程
that hopefully it's clear some of you, if not all of you,
希望你们中的一些人，即使不是全部，
we're doing finality on these like longer time scales.
我们在这些较长的时间尺度上执行最终性。
And this is like, again, this finality gadget
这再次就像这个最终的小工具
it's providing finality, but then even within, you know,
它提供了最终性，但是即使在内部，您也知道
one epoch, e plus one, within one epoch itself, we're also using this LMD ghost protocol to figure
一个时期，E加一个，在一个时期内，我们还使用此LMD幽灵协议来弄清楚
out the actual tip of the chain. So when I go to produce the next block, I need to pick this block
消除链的实际尖端。因此，当我去制作下一个块时，我需要选择这个块
or this block. And yeah, Gaspar is just basically our particular instantiation of this consensus
或这个块。是的，Gaspar基本上是我们对此共识的特殊实例
protocol that's like ffg plus lmd goes
就像FFG Plus LMD一样的协议
thank you
谢谢
um yeah i think that's probably all we have time for today unless mario you have another question
嗯，是的，除非马里奥还有一个问题，否则我认为这可能是我们今天有时间
yeah i wanted to if we can just touch on the pbs for a second there was a question we are going to
是的，我想如果我们只能碰到PBS一秒钟，我们将要解决一个问题
dive into it more, but you are the man, and it's it's I think it's a good chance to just
更多地深入研究，但你是男人，这是我认为这是一个很好的机会
briefly, we are out of time. So if you can touch on that. What's the motivation? What's
简而言之，我们没有时间。因此，如果您可以谈谈。什么动机？是什么
the workings of proposal builder separation?
提案建造者分离的工作？
Right. So yeah, I wanted to start from basics, basically, and go from zero to how
正确的。是的，我想从基本知识开始，然后从零开始到如何
as it uses protocol work.
因为它使用协议工作。
And it turns out that, you know,
事实证明，你知道，
this protocol lives in the real world
该协议生活在现实世界中
and there's like so many other things
还有很多其他事情
that I don't have time to go into today,
我今天没有时间去
but basically have been consequences of the system.
但基本上是系统的后果。
So, yeah, I actually maybe will just write,
所以，是的，我实际上也许只会写，
I did have a few more things in my notes
我的笔记中确实还有一些东西
around like a few things here.
像这里一样的几件事。
So, you know, just kind of looking at like the future
所以，你知道，就像未来一样
of this proof-of-stake protocol
该验证协议的
and Ethereum generally, right?
一般来说，以太坊吧？
There's a bunch of things that we wanna kinda do.
我们想做很多事情。
One of them is like single slot finality, SSF.
其中之一就像单个插槽最终命名，SSF。
And this is basically saying like, for many reasons,
这基本上是在说，出于许多原因，
I, again, I don't really have time to get into,
我再次没有时间进入，
but because of the fact that you have
但是由于你有事实
this dynamic availability,
这种动态可用性，
then there's both games sort of happening here
然后这两个游戏都在这里发生
that also impact this like, epoch level thing.
这也影响了这类时代水平的事情。
And it turns out there are like many different attacks
事实证明，有许多不同的攻击
that others can pull off with this flexibility.
其他人可以通过这种灵活性来实现。
And so rather than have this like finality process,
因此，与其具有这样的最终过程，而是
like trail say like two epochs behind the chain,
就像小径一样，就像链条后面的两个时代一样
you would actually wanna look at getting finality
您实际上想考虑获得最终期限
within a single slot.
在一个插槽中。
And again, single slot finality,
再一次，单个插槽终结，
that can then should be pretty clear.
那应该很清楚。
That's one thing.
那是一回事。
Other things, I mean, yeah,
其他事情，我的意思是，是的，
I guess I'll just like write out what I have as SLE.
我想我会喜欢写出我的sle。
So this is basically, you'd want to make proposal selection
因此，这基本上是您要选择建议的
be kind of secret or like just in time.
有点秘密或像及时一样。
Like the idea is that as a validator,
就像想法一样，作为验证者，
so today you actually can go and look at the chain.
因此，今天您实际上可以去看看链条。
And based on the Randolph thing that I talked about,
并基于我谈论的伦道夫（Randolph）
you actually know one to two epochs ahead of time
您实际上会提前一到两个时期
who the proposer is.
建议者是谁。
This is not great because, you know,
这不是很好，因为，你知道，
this is an open decentralized network.
这是一个开放的分散网络。
I can actually go and be a various like network techniques.
我实际上可以成为一种类似的网络技术。
I can actually like identify on the peer-to-peer layer,
我实际上可以在对等层上识别，
which IPs or which validators, for example.
例如，IPS或哪个验证器。
Once I have your IP, if I don't like your block,
一旦我拥有您的IP，如果我不喜欢您的块，
that's gonna come up in your slots,
那会在你的老虎机中出现
I can actually try to DOS you.
我实际上可以尝试让你。
And so one way that we can improve upon this
因此，一种方法可以改善这一点
is basically get into a place where
基本上是进入一个地方
the next proposer is actually like secret,
下一个建议者实际上就像秘密一样，
like until, you know, just in time almost,
就像直到您知道，直到及时几乎及时
where they have to like reveal some,
他们必须喜欢透露一些地方，
some like election ticket, let's say,
有些人喜欢选举票，假设
to actually have a valid block.
实际上有一个有效的块。
There's other things, max-eb is one.
还有其他事情，Max-Eb是一个。
So this is getting it it's like 32 ETH balance.
因此，这就像32 ETH平衡。
And you could imagine basically making it so that
您可以想象基本上这样做
rather than sort of making one validator have 32 ETH,
而不是让一个验证者有32个ETH，而是
they could have like, I don't know,
他们可能会喜欢，我不知道，
so much higher number say 2048.
如此之多的数字是2048。
This is important because right now, if I have say like,
这很重要，因为现在，如果我说的话，
yeah, again, I don't know, 64 ETH,
是的，再次，我不知道，64 ETH，
that must be two validators in the protocol.
那必须是协议中的两个验证者。
And this is partly how we got
这是我们得到的部分原因
to like such a high number of validators
喜欢如此大量的验证者
is like, it happened to this unit's a 32.
就像，这件事发生在该单元32中。
Many people have, you know, much more than 32 ETH,
您知道，许多人拥有超过32个ETH，
like these big, like professional staking operations,
像这些大型，像专业的Staking Operations一样，
for example.
例如。
And so you can imagine having one validator entity
因此，您可以想象拥有一个验证器实体
in the protocol with like a much higher balance.
在协议中，平衡得多。
And this lets you consolidate the set.
这使您可以合并该集合。
That's something, there's also like, yeah,
那是什么，也有，是的，
there's like penalty campaigns we've been looking at
我们一直在研究的惩罚运动
to actually like make the staking situation
实际上喜欢使静止状况
or the slashing situation a bit better.
或削减情况更好。
um there's the whole economics itself there's no like issuance around when values are rewarded
嗯，整个经济学本身都没有奖励价值的发行
things like how that that goes into them and anyway okay i'm just like brain death and stuff
诸如此类的事情，无论如何好吧，我就像脑死亡和其他东西
now um that all being said let me answer your question which is about pbs so this is another
现在，所有人都说让我回答您的问题，这是另一个
thing very much top of mind uh for all the x's researchers so we have pbs proposer builder
对于所有X的研究人员来说
separation. And yeah, so the idea here is that the protocol doesn't exist in a vacuum.
分离。是的，所以这里的想法是该协议不存在于真空中。
There's this very valuable execution layer, and there's this notion of MEV. And it used to stand
有一个非常有价值的执行层，有MEV的概念。它曾经站立
for maximum extractable value. The idea is that basically, when I go, I mean, let's see,
最大可提取值。想法是，从根本上来说，当我走时，我的意思是，让我们看看，看看
what's a good image I could use? Well, let me just start over. So when I keep drawing my box
我可以使用什么好图像？好吧，让我重新开始。所以当我继续画盒子时
that I have and I have my transactions it turns out that like some sequence of transactions could
我拥有的，我有交易，事实证明，就像某些交易序列一样
be more valuable than another um and yeah I don't really have time to go into like the specifics of
比另一个UM更有价值，是的，我真的没有时间像
that but ultimately um the way to think about this is that there is this notion of MEV where
那但最终想到这一点的方式是，有一个梅夫的概念
uh you know it's better uh to be sophisticated better to be sophisticated
嗯，你知道更好的是要成熟的更好
as a validator
作为验证器
in part so you can like extract this MEV,
部分使您可以提取此MEV，
which I don't know,
我不知道，
I'll just try to draw some coins or something.
我只是尝试画一些硬币或其他东西。
But basically there's this notion
但基本上有这个概念
that you're kind of leaving money on the table
你有点把钱留在桌子上
if you're like not pulling in
如果你想不加入
these more sophisticated techniques to build blocks.
这些更复杂的技术来构建块。
And this is a problem
这是一个问题
because it basically harms the centralization.
因为它基本上会损害集中化。
Why?
为什么？
Because let's say some other validator
因为假设其他一些验证者
is better at me at extracting this MEV.
我更好地提取此MEV。
They can, for example, offer better returns.
例如，他们可以提供更好的回报。
They can attract more stake.
他们可以吸引更多的股份。
And now there's this flywheel where you have big, massive staking pools all run by, say, one entity.
现在有了这个飞轮，您拥有大量大量的堆放池，例如一个实体。
And then now, rather than have actually a million nodes that are all working together to secure Ethereum,
然后，现在，实际上没有一个有共同努力以确保以太坊的节点，而是
there's now maybe just five or some smaller number,
现在可能只有五个或较小的数字，
perhaps in jurisdictional areas that are not favorable to certain Ethereum transactions.
也许在不利于某些以太坊交易的管辖区。
So we want to stop this.
所以我们想停止这个。
And generally the way that we think about this right now is PBS, where you kind of want to separate off this task of making the execution block.
通常，我们现在对此的考虑是PBS，您想将执行块的任务分开。
So yeah, maybe I'll draw CL Neo.
是的，也许我会画CL Neo。
There's now a CL block here with an execution payload that goes inside.
现在，这里有一个CL块，内部有执行有效负载。
And with PBS, you actually want to think about separating these two.
使用PBS，您实际上想考虑将这两个分开。
So that you can outsource building this thing, this execution payload, which is becoming a very sophisticated task, to some other entity.
这样您就可以将构建此内容的外包，此执行有效负载，这已成为一些非常复杂的任务。
we'll call it a builder um and then as a validator you don't have to like play these like very
我们将其称为建造者UM，然后作为验证器，您不必喜欢像玩这些一样
sophisticated games you can just again outsource this to someone and then still uh profit from the
复杂的游戏您可以再次将其外包给某人，然后仍然从中获利
work that was pbs in like one minute i hope that was helpful yeah that was great thanks alex
在一分钟内是PBS的工作，我希望这很有帮助，这真是太好了，谢谢Alex
uh cool yeah i think we're about 15 minutes over here so i think we probably should wrap it up
嗯，是的，我想我们在这里大约15分钟，所以我认为我们可能应该把它包裹起来
um but yeah thanks so much for giving us a nice overview into the consensus layer um i'm sure
嗯，是的，非常感谢您给我们一个很好的共识层的概述嗯，我敢肯定
there are some questions that didn't get answered uh and so hopefully alex can join our discord
有一些问题没有得到回答，所以希望亚历克斯能加入我们的不和谐
server and see if there's anything in there that he wants to dive into um
服务器，看看他是否有任何东西要潜入UM
yeah thanks again alex and uh we will see you all next week for a dive into testing
是的，再次感谢亚历克斯，嗯，下周我们将见到大家进行测试
thank you so much
太感谢了
Alex
亚历克斯
we appreciate
我们感谢
your time man
你的时间男人
yeah
是的
yeah it was fun
是的，这很有趣
thanks for having me
谢谢你有我
and yeah
是的
I'll reach out
我会伸出援手
to any of you
给你们任何一个
to get in the discord
进入不和谐
and I'm happy
我很高兴
to answer
回答
some more questions
还有一些问题
there
那里
so
所以
thanks everyone
谢谢大家
and yeah
是的
I'll see you around
我会在周围见
thank you so much
太感谢了
yeah
是的
great
伟大的
bye
再见
and
和
for everyone
为每个人
still listening
还在听
please
请
take all the
全力以赴
great materials and questions answered and everything that was discussed in the talk
很棒的材料和问题回答以及谈话中讨论的一切
and the Discord chat and open PR Tweaky, feel free to add it to the corresponding doc or
以及Discord聊天和打开的调整，请随时将其添加到相应的文档或
create a new one.
创建一个新的。
We have a bunch of great contributions, so please keep it coming.
我们有很多巨大的贡献，所以请继续前进。
And yeah, thank you so much for joining us today for the Consensus Layer Talk.
是的，非常感谢您今天加入我们的共识层谈话。
Thanks, everybody.
谢谢，大家。
We'll see you on Thursday on the Hangout call.
我们将在周四的聊天电话中与您见面。
Yeah.
是的。
I want to mention that as well.
我也想提一下。
So yeah, if you want to just, you know, chat with us, discuss maybe what would you like
是的，如果您想知道，请与我们聊天，讨论您想要什么
to work on, contribute in the Wiki or just like, you know, maybe even outside of the
要进行工作，在Wiki中做出贡献，或者就像在
Ethereum, come to chat with us in the call.
以太坊，在电话中与我们聊天。
You can find the event on the Discord server.
您可以在Discord服务器上找到事件。
Thanks a lot.
多谢。
Excellent.
出色的。
Thank you.
谢谢。